music
音楽
applause
拍手
Today's Feast of Knowledge
今日の知識の饗宴
So first I would like to introduce today's keynote speaker
それではまず、本日の基調講演者をご紹介したいと思います
Today's speaker is Academician Zhang Zhenghua
今日の講演者は学術士の張正華氏です。
So
それで
I think everyone should be familiar with his name.
誰もが彼の名前を知っているはずだと思います。
Well, Academician Zhang is a world-renowned archaeologist
さて、張学者は世界的に有名な考古学者です
He is the Department of Archaeological Anthropology of National Taiwan University
彼は国立台湾大学考古人類学部です。
Graduated from the School of Archeology and Anthropology, National Taiwan University
国立台湾大学考古人類学部卒業
yes then graduating from harvard
はい、それではハーバード大学を卒業します
So he has actually been from
それで、彼は実際に出身です
from his first job
彼の最初の仕事から
at the Institute of Historical Linguistics at Academia Sinica
中央研究院歴史言語学研究所にて
then now as a Distinguished Research Fellow
その後、現在は特別研究員として
His research information is mainly Taiwan
研究情報は主に台湾
Realization culture in South China and Southeast Asia
中国南部と東南アジアの実現文化
over the past 40 years
過去40年間にわたって
He has led more than a dozen large-scale projects
彼は十数件の大規模プロジェクトを指揮してきました。
large archaeological project
大規模な考古学プロジェクト
Including the excavation of the very famous Shisanhang ruins
非常に有名な十三行遺跡の発掘を含む
Archaeological Survey of the Grand Ducey Valley
グランド・デューシー・バレーの考古学調査
Archaeological research on the history of ancient human extension
古代人類の拡張の歴史に関する考古学的研究
Archaeological Research on the North Shore of the Philippines
フィリピンのノースショアにおける考古学調査
But the most interesting thing to draw attention to is the
しかし、最も注目すべき点は、
started more than ten years ago
10年以上前に始めた
Nanke Ancient Culture This
南柯古代文化はこちら
Rescue plan for ruins
廃墟の救出計画
Nananke Ancient Cultural Relics Rescue Project Institute
南科古代文化財救出プロジェクト研究所
Many cultural relics unearthed
多くの文化遺物が出土
this
これ
The importance of academic significance
学術的意義の重要性
i think it's hard to have
持つのは難しいと思う
comparable to this
これに匹敵する
in 2009
2009年に
Mr. Zhang has given many tasks to Taitung County at the Ministry of Culture
張氏は文化部で台東県に多くの任務を与えてきた。
Entrusted the implementation of Taitung Changbing's
台東長兵の実装を受託
Baxiandong National Site Survey Project
八仙洞国家遺跡調査プロジェクト
that's because of this
それはこのせいだ
What I'm doing at this time is the director
このとき私がやっていることはディレクターです
Year 2009
2009年
I am the late director
私は故監督です
so i know all of this
だから私はこれをすべて知っています
I have also visited the ruins of Nanke
南柯遺跡にも行ってきました
I also offered
私も提供しました
Unearthed skeletons of many people across the ages
時代を超えて多くの人々の骸骨が発掘される
I forgot whether it was Zhang Xian or who told me
張賢だったのか、誰が教えてくれたのか忘れた
Someday these cars will be brought back to the research institute
いつかこの車も研究所に持ち帰るだろう
I was shocked
私はショックを受けました
Because there is no place in the research institute to put so many
研究所にはそんなにたくさん置く場所はないので
Maybe I don't know if it's Zhang Xian or who was the staff at that time
たぶん、それが張賢なのか、それとも当時のスタッフだったのかわかりません。
when joking
冗談を言うとき
because a lot
たくさんあるので
very large
非常に大きい
So Baxiandong Chair
蘇八仙洞チェア
After four years of intensive and systematic investigation
4年間にわたる集中的かつ体系的な調査を経て
Determined the chronology and cultural connotation of Taiwan's old culture
台湾の古い文化の歴史と文化的意味合いを明らかにする
Push back the history of human beings living in Taiwan to 30,000 years ago
台湾に住んでいた人類の歴史を3万年前まで遡る
So this is a very important project
ですから、これは非常に重要なプロジェクトです
besides
そのほか
Academician Zhang is also keen on applying archaeology to social services
学者の張氏は考古学を社会福祉に応用することにも熱心である
i think you remember
あなたは覚えていると思います
Last time this TransAsia Airways
前回はトランスアジア航空
Unfortunately, this plane is the best
残念ながら、この飛行機が最高です
In the end, there was no way Mr. Zhang led the archaeological team
結局、張氏が考古学チームを率いることはできなかった
with the most sophisticated detectors
最も洗練された検出器を備えた
At that time, the TV interviewed Mr. Zhang
その時、テレビは張さんにインタビューした。
I have seen
私は見た
I think you may have seen
たぶん見たことあると思います
He often assists the government in carrying out the work of preserving cultural assets
彼は政府による文化財の保存活動を手伝うことが多い
And from 2002 to 2006
そして2002年から2006年まで
Curator of the National Taiwan Shijie Culture Museum
国立台湾世集文化博物館学芸員
There are many contributions to this Shijie cultural museum
この石街文化博物館には多くの寄稿があります
He also leads the commission of the socio-cultural museum
彼は社会文化博物館の委員会も率いています。
Leading the Academia Sinica underwater archeology team
中央研究院水中考古学チームを率いる
There has also now been quite a bit of investigation
現在もかなりの調査が行われています
grades
成績匪然
Please don't underestimate underwater archeology
水中考古学を過小評価しないでください
Because at this time I am also the director
このとき私はディレクターでもあるので、
So to train in underwater archaeology
それで水中考古学の訓練を受けるために
I want to dive to Ximan in a fast class seaside place in Taoyuan
桃園のファストクラスの海辺で西満へダイビングしたい
The film is very capable of continuing when you and I go to support
あなたと私が応援に行くとき、映画はとても続きます。
I still remember
まだ覚えている
that was very hard work
それはとても大変な仕事でした
The trainee program
研修生プログラム
so this works
それでこれはうまくいきます
and it's groundbreaking
そしてそれは画期的です
Taiwan did not have such a
台湾にはそんなものなかった
Formal Archaeological Team
正式な考古学チーム
underwater archeology team
水中考古学チーム
He also currently serves as
現在は以下の役職も務めている
Chairman of the Chinese Association of Underwater Archaeology
中国水中考古学協会会長
promote civil participation
市民参加を促進する
Protection and promotion of underwater cultural assets
水中文化財の保護と振興
That Mr. Zhang has a lot of trials
張氏には多くの試練があったということ
There are many wind industry crises
風力発電業界の危機は数多くある
There is no way to introduce Yiyi here
ここでYiyiを紹介する方法はありません
The topic he is going to talk about today is
彼が今日話そうとしているテーマは
Stories of Ancient Taiwanese
古代台湾の物語
we welcome him with warm applause
私たちは温かい拍手で彼を歓迎します
thank you very much
どうもありがとうございます
Vice President Wang
王副院長
Vice President Wang just gave me an introduction
王副社長が私に紹介をしてくれました。
actually
実際
Vice President Wang is my old officer
王副総統は私の昔の役員です
In the past, he was our director when he was in the eleventh institute
以前、彼は第 11 研究所にいたときに私たちの所長でした。
now our vice president
今では私たちの副社長
So a lot of things he just said
彼が今言った多くのこと
under his leadership
彼のリーダーシップの下で
can be executed smoothly
スムーズに実行できる
then i personally
それから私は個人的に
In fact, time is very fast in this field
実際、この分野では時間が経つのが非常に速いです
It's been 40 years all of a sudden
あっという間に40年経ってしまった
this time is very long
今回はとても長いです
Actually in all my work
実際、私のすべての仕事において
The last thing that came together was this
最後に集まったのはこれです
Stories of Ancient Taiwanese
古代台湾の物語
because of my expertise
私の専門知識のせいで
Although I also work in surrounding areas of Taiwan
私も台湾近郊で仕事をしていますが、
Archeology of Mainland Southeast Asia
東南アジア本土の考古学
But after all, Taiwan is still me
でも結局のところ、台湾はまだ私なのです
main field of work
主な仕事分野
So in the past 30-40 years
それで、ここ30～40年の間に
Actually the work I do
実は私がやっている仕事は
The ultimate purpose is to go
最終的な目的は行くことです
The stories of ancient people in Taiwan
台湾の古代人の物語
able to piece together
つなぎ合わせることができる
So I bring up this topic today
そこで今日はこの話題を取り上げます
I think the story of the ancient Taiwanese
古代台湾人の物語だと思います
let me talk for an hour and a half
1時間半話させてください
Actually, I think that what you say
実際、あなたの言うことはそのとおりだと思います
It should be like a thousand and one nights
千夜一夜みたいになるはず
just tell a story
ただ話をしてください
Really can add a lot of stories
本当にたくさんのストーリーを追加できます
But today I can only be very general
でも今日はごく一般的なことしか言えません
very simply
とても単純に
Let's talk about the story of this ancient Taiwanese
この古代台湾人の物語について話しましょう
Of course, this story is not One Thousand and One Nights.
もちろん、この物語は千夜一夜物語ではありません。
just one night it won't arrive
一晩だけでは届かない
Then I say today is easy
それなら今日は簡単だと言うよ
if anything is unclear
何か不明な点がある場合は
Also please give me advice
また、アドバイスをお願いします
So
それで
My computer here is not very
ここのコンピューターの調子はあまり良くありません
OK
OK
This is another page
これは別のページです
Originally, this mouse should be able to change a page
本来、このマウスはページを変更できるはずです
I don't know why it can't be changed
なぜ変更できないのかわかりません
this can be replaced
これは交換できます
this is ok
これで結構です
sorry for this
ごめんなさい
no page change
ページ変更なし
here
ここ
ok good
いいよ
then i want this
それならこれが欲しいです
Before today's story, I will make a beginning
今日の物語の前に始まりを作ります
then i want to be in taiwan
それなら台湾に行きたいです
One of the most familiar questions is that Taiwanese people
最もよくある質問の 1 つは、台湾の人々です。
I think everyone in the media is on the news
メディア関係者全員がニュースに取り上げていると思います
Go online and check Google
インターネットにアクセスして Google をチェックしてください
This very, very much these discussions
これは非常に非常にこれらの議論です
these discussions these coups
これらの議論、これらのクーデター
So this Taiwan as a look at all kinds of
さて、この台湾のあらゆる種類の様子を見てみましょう
the same view
同じ景色
Well in fact there are many
まぁ実際にはたくさんあるんですが
It stems from a different view of history
それは歴史観の違いから来ている
We can't say who is right and who is wrong
誰が正しくて誰が間違っているのかは言えません
but basically
しかし基本的には
This is due to many different historical views
これはさまざまな歴史的見解によるものです
Well, I'll just list a few now.
さて、今からいくつか列挙してみます。
Then the first and most famous is
次に、最初で最も有名なのは、
Lianheng's Taiwan General Studies
連恒の台湾総合研究
Then this as a view of history
それでは、これは歴史的な観点として
It is basically the historical view of the consciousness of the Han nationality
基本的には漢民族の意識の歴史観です
So from its Taiwan general knowledge sequence
台湾の一般知識シーケンスから
It says Taiwan is not true
台湾は真実ではないと言う
Who started it is exactly what made it
誰がそれを始めたのか、それがまさにそれを作った人です
Yingzhi in the Qing Dynasty Enlightenment also has a temper
清朝啓蒙の英志にも気性がある
As for more than three hundred years ago
300年以上前のことのように
then this obviously
それからこれは明らかに
It is a Chinese perspective
それは中国の視点です
such a view of history
そういう歴史観
that this
これは
Then another very famous
それからもう一つとても有名な
it's totally different
それは全く違います
in the opposite direction
一反方向的
This is the famous historical name
これは有名な歴史的な名前です
It says to write the four hundred years history of Taiwanese
台湾四百年の歴史を書くと書いてある
you see it in front of it
目の前にそれが見えます
He also said that general laws concerning the development of human society
彼はまた、人間社会の発展に関する一般法則についても述べた。
the universal truth of social development
社会発展の普遍的な真実
Combined with these historical realities of Taiwan
こうした台湾の歴史的現実と組み合わせると、
Then try to grasp the reality of Taiwan
ならば台湾の現実を掴んでみよう
Re-establish Taiwan's view of history
台湾の歴史観を再確立する
So one of his views on history
それで、彼の歴史観の一つは、
Basically based on the development of Taiwan's national theory
基本的には台湾国家論の発展に基づく
a view of history developed
発展した歴史観
What about another historian?
他の歴史家はどうでしょうか？
This is the vice president of our college in the past
これは私たちの大学の以前の副学長です
Where is Vice President Zhang Guangzhe?
張光哲副総統はどこにいますか？
Then one of his views on history
それから彼の歴史観の一つが
so what did he say
それで彼は何と言ったのか
He is due to Taiwan's island environment
彼は台湾の島の環境によるものです
Complexity of geography and terrain
地理と地形の複雑さ
What about our research on Taiwan history?
台湾の歴史についての研究はどうですか？
And we must adopt a more obvious perspective of cultural ecology
そして私たちは文化生態学についてより明白な視点を採用する必要があります
And because the 2 billion indigenous peoples on Taiwan Island
そして、台湾島には20億人の先住民族がいます。
Therefore, the history of Taiwan contains a very important history of indigenous peoples
したがって、台湾の歴史には、先住民族の非常に重要な歴史が含まれています。
The New Components of the Relationship with the Han Dynasty
漢王朝との関係の新たな要素
So he learned from the cultural ecology of an entire island
そこで彼は島全体の文化生態学から学びました
such a point of view
そのような視点
the relationship between the person
人と人との関係
This view of human interaction
この人間関係の見方
to develop
開発する
one of his views on history
彼の歴史観の一つ
Another recent one
もう一つ最近のもの
Cao Yong and Academician Cao who just passed away
亡くなったばかりの曹勇と曹学者
Then what he proposed
そこで彼が提案したのは、
Also known as Taiwan Island History View
台湾島歴史観としても知られています。
so he thinks
それで彼は考えます
Our Research on the Island of Taiwan
台湾島での調査
should get rid of these political
こういう政治的なものは排除すべきだ
these positions
これらの立場
some of these politics
これらの政治のいくつか
Some perspectives on change
変化についてのいくつかの視点
Rather, from the history of the people on the island of Taiwan
むしろ、台湾島の人々の歴史から
Just a separate from this island
この島とはちょっと離れたところにある
a stage of history
歴史の一段階
to explain the development of our Taiwan
私たちの台湾の発展を説明するために
Therefore, from the perspective of Taiwan island history
そこで、台湾島の歴史の観点から見ると、
to provide such a
そのようなものを提供するために
A Viewpoint on Taiwan's History
台湾の歴史への視点
So because of this different view of history
したがって、この異なる歴史観
tends to develop naturally
自然に発達する傾向がある
for taiwan
台湾向け
who is taiwanese
台湾人は誰ですか
such an issue
そのような問題
there will be something different
何か違うことがあるだろう
some opinions
いくつかのビュー
this is very much
これはとても
check as if
あたかもチェックする
on the media
メディアで
on the page
ページ上で
various of these
これらのさまざまな
Randomly list out a few
ランダムにいくつか挙げてみます
result everyone
結果はみんな
He has different viewpoints
彼はさまざまな視点を持っています
leftist
左翼
There are also various viewpoints
色々な見方もありますが
So these things have actually become a big kind of entanglement in our Taiwanese society today, or one left over two.
つまり、これらのことは、実際、今日の台湾社会において大きな一種のしがらみになっている、つまり、1 つが 2 つ残っているということです。
disturbance
妨害
so what about me today
それで今日の私はどうですか
I'm a person who studies archaeology. What's the advantage?
私は考古学を研究している人間なのですが、どんなメリットがあるのでしょうか？
I can ignore people now
今では人を無視できるようになりました
because people are alive now
人は今生きているから
right
右
to speak face to face
面と向かって話すこと
to see
見る
to discuss
話し合う
to argue
主張する
but what about me today
でも今日の私はどうだろうか
I met the ancient people
古代の人々に出会った
So it's simpler
だからもっとシンプルです
then i want this
それならこれが欲しいです
After the research of this ancient man
この古代人の研究の後
What can we do with our research
私たちの研究で何ができるのか
go back and think about it
戻って考えてみてください
who is taiwanese
台湾人は誰ですか
Then their survival and development trajectory in Taiwan
台湾における彼らの生存と発展の軌跡
but what
でも何
What are the traits they can conceive?
彼らはどのような特徴を思いつくのでしょうか？
Then what
じゃあ何
What about us Taiwanese today?
今の私たち台湾人はどうでしょうか？
What kind of inspiration can he offer
彼はどんなインスピレーションを提供してくれるだろうか
I think this is what we actually
これが私たちの実際の姿だと思います
Generally speaking, we archaeologists
一般的に言えば、私たち考古学者は、
Is an ivory tower of knowledge
象牙の知識の塔です
We just locked ourselves in an ivory tower to do research
私たちは研究をするために象牙の塔に閉じ​​込められただけです
has nothing to do with today's society
今日の社会とは何の関係もありません
I think this is a completely wrong point of view
これは完全に間違った視点だと思います
In fact, Vice President Wang also explained just now
実は今、王副総統も説明しました。
actually
実際
We who do archaeology don't just care about society
考古学をやっている私たちは社会のことだけを考えているわけではありません
And many of them are actually closely related to society.
そしてそれらの多くは実際に社会と密接に関係しています。
these interactions
これらの相互作用
Just now, Wangfu mentioned that the recent complex air crash
たった今、王府は最近の複雑な航空事故について言及しました。
We actually have a place where archeology can play our role
実際、私たちには考古学が役割を果たすことができる場所があります
We can also use our expertise
私たちの専門知識も活用できます
To assist in this financial river
この金融の川を助けるために
Go hunt for these scumbags of this plane crash
この飛行機事故のクソ野郎どもを捜しに行こう
Well, of course there are many other developments in our society
もちろん、私たちの社会には他にも多くの発展があります
some cultural issues
いくつかの文化的な問題
In fact, archaeologists are very active in participating in
実際、考古学者は非常に積極的に参加しています。
So we have a saying
そこで私たちには格言があります
Archaeologists from Taiwan
台湾の考古学者
His other name is Fire Brigade
彼の別名は消防団です
Because he went to fight the fire all day and night
彼は昼も夜も消火活動に行ったから
Because there are too many things in Taiwan that need cultural rescue
台湾には文化的な救済が必要なものが多すぎるため
Most of the many archaeologists came and went to serve as
多くの考古学者のほとんどは、
So like environmental image assessment to do EIA work
EIA作業を行うための環境画像評価のようなものです
Many archaeologists also participated in
考古学者も多数参加
So in fact, archaeologists and today's society
実際、考古学者と今日の社会は
In fact, there is a very close relationship between these
実はこれらの間には非常に密接な関係があるのです
So many modern issues
現代の問題がたくさんある
also from some different viewpoints
いくつかの異なる視点からも
to provide some thoughts
いくつかの考えを提供するために
so what
だから何
But how to meet the ancients
しかし、古代人に会うにはどうすればよいですか
how to see ancient people
古代人をどう見るか
i want this one
私はこれがほしいです
These ancient people have disappeared
この古代の人々は消えてしまった
completely gone
完全になくなった
but luckily
しかし幸運にも
what about these ancient people
この古代の人々はどうですか
he walked back
彼は歩いて戻った
he did the opposite
彼はそれを逆にやった
He must have left some traces
彼は何らかの痕跡を残したに違いない
What about archaeologists?
考古学者はどうでしょうか？
Through the clues of these clues
これらの手がかりを手がかりに
What about these studies and these analyzes?
これらの研究や分析についてはどうですか?
we still
私たちはまだ
there is still a chance
まだチャンスはある
Can meet ancient people
古代人に会える
so this is
それでこれは
what about archaeologists
考古学者はどうですか
a job that can be done
できる仕事
Then the data of archaeological research
それから考古学的研究のデータ
probably basically
おそらく基本的には
mainly through the legacy of these substances
主にこれらの物質の遺産を通じて
because the ancient people
なぜなら古代の人たちは
what about immaterial things
非物質的なものについてはどうですか
has disappeared
消えました
right
右
because it looks like some
何かに似ているので
What can't be saved?
何が救われないのか？
all gone
全部なくなった
He said he could stay
彼はここにいてもいいと言った
Basically these are these remnants of matter
基本的にこれらは物質の残骸です
And inside the material
そして素材の中には
Because basically it's these
基本的にはこれなので
non-organic
非有機的
or non-perishable
または腐らないもの
to survive
生き残るために
This thing has become the treasure of archaeologists
これは考古学者の宝物になった
Archaeologists use these things
考古学者はこれらのものを使用します
To be able to get close to these ancient humans
この古代人たちに近づくことができるということ
So what about our research data?
では、私たちの研究データはどうなるのでしょうか？
basically contains these relics
基本的にこれらの遺物が含まれています
ruins and ruins
廃墟と廃墟
These are the main materials we studied
これらは私たちが研究した主な材料です
then these things are archaeologists
じゃあ、こいつらは考古学者だ
Regardless of porcelain naughty stoneware
磁器に関係なくいたずらなせっ器
Regardless of the legacy of these plants, the legacy of animals
これらの植物の遺産に関係なく、動物の遺産は
These are basically as long as archaeologists can discover
これらは基本的に考古学者が発見できる限りの長さです
It can be used as these materials for its research
これらの研究材料として使用できます
Then there are other so-called relics
それから、他のいわゆる遺物があります
It is some phenomena left over by ancient humans.
それは古代人類が残したいくつかの現象です。
or some structure
あるいは何らかの構造物
So what can be found?
それで何が見つかるでしょうか？
it can also be important
それは重要なこともある
A material for archaeological research
考古学研究の資料
So as for the acquisition of these materials
では、これらの資料の入手については
Archaeologists are two methods
考古学者には2つの方法があります
an archaeological survey
考古学的調査
The other is to do archaeological excavations
もう一つは考古学的発掘です
archaeological investigation
考古学調査
Just go to the wild to find it when it rains
雨が降ったら野生に行って見つけてください
through your pastor
あなたの牧師を通して
through this drill of yours
あなたのこのドリルを通して
Even through some scientific means
たとえ何らかの科学的手段を介しても
like this one using ground penetrating radar
これは地中レーダーを使用したものです
or other scientific means
または他の科学的手段
Come help us find the ancients
古代人を見つけるのを手伝ってください
these ruins
これらの遺跡
or relic
または遺物
so-called clues
いわゆる手がかり
able to find out
知ることができる
So so this part
それでこの部分は
I give an example
例を挙げます
Just now Vice President Wang mentioned
先ほど王副主席が言及しました。
We are in Tainan Science Park
私たちは台南サイエンスパークにいます
Doing this archaeological investigation work for more than ten years
この考古学調査の仕事を10年以上続けている
We are all through this method
私たちは皆この方法を経験しています
do research first
まずリサーチをする
through various means
さまざまな手段を通じて
including these simplest
これらの最も単純なものを含めて
just walk to observe
ただ歩いて観察するだけ
some drill
いくつかのドリル
There are also some scientific
科学的なものもある
means of detection
検出手段
want to discover in this area
このエリアで発見したい
buried under the ground
地面の下に埋もれている
The remains of these ancient humans
これらの古代人類の遺跡
including ruins
遺跡も含めて
or birth relics
または誕生の遺物
So so we're in this Nanke area
ということで、ここ南柯地区に来ました。
just found out you see
わかりました
A Nanke found so many of these remnants
南家はこれらの残骸を非常に多く発見した
what about these ruins
これらの遺跡はどうですか
It represents different worlds
さまざまな世界を表現しています
on this land
この土地で
all these clues that flowed down
流れてきたこれらすべての手がかり
through this thread
このスレッドを通じて
to the people of this land
この土地の人々に
can have more understanding
より多くの理解を得ることができる
still understand
まだ理解できる
This is our other method
これは私たちの別の方法です
is to excavate
発掘することです
Some people joked about relying on scholars
学者に頼ることを冗談にする人もいた
You have relied on scholars
あなたは学者に頼りました
hole by hole
穴ごとに
what are you doing
あなたは何をしている
This is called weasel burrowing
これをイタチ穴掘りといいます
Look, this is really a hole
見てください、これは本当に穴です
In fact, our hole
実際、私たちの穴は
It is also a learned method
それも習得した方法です
from the hole
穴から
to be very systematic
非常に体系的であること
Take these clues of ancient humans
古代人類に関するこれらの手がかりを入手してください
can be found systematically
体系的に見つけることができる
then do research
それから研究をしてください
do patchwork
パッチワークをする
sorry
ごめん
do you see us
私たちを見ていますか
Weasel has burrowed
イタチが穴を掘った
punch so many holes
たくさんの穴を開ける
You see, this hole is actually
ほら、この穴は実は
are very systematic
非常に体系的です
Because the future underground
未来の地下だから
anything
なんでも
We all have very detailed records
私たちは皆、非常に詳細な記録を持っています
it is known
周知された
where did this come from
これはどこから来たのですか
after you come out in the future
将来出てきた後
when it comes to putting it together
それをまとめるとき
with the help of this system
このシステムの助けを借りて
this program
このプログラム
and can be completed
そして完了することができます
Where are we in this Greedy Science Park?
私たちはこの貪欲なサイエンスパークのどこにいるのでしょうか？
did these on a very large scale
これらは非常に大規模に行われました
salvage these excavations
これらの発掘物を回収する
investigation
調査
So Chen Ru just said that Vice President Wang
そこで陳如は先ほど王副総統が言った。
we have tons of these relics
私たちはこれらの遺物をたくさん持っています
So Central Court
それで中央裁判所
He dare not let us ship back
彼は私たちに返送させようとはしませんでした
after shipping back
返送後
He's going to help us build several houses
彼は私たちがいくつかの家を建てるのを手伝うつもりです
this is the most difficult thing
これが最も難しいことです
I believe
私は信じている
then for these
それではこれらについて
These materials were unearthed
こういった資料が出土したのです
Whether it's a relic
遺物だろうか
Of course our next
もちろん次は
we have to analyze
私たちは分析しなければなりません
to study
勉強する
If you do not analyze the research
研究を分析しないと
Impossible this pair is trash
ありえない、このペアはゴミだ
but it can never have any effect
しかしそれは何の効果もありません
Then we have to do a lot of analysis
その後、多くの分析を行う必要があります
So archaeologists work very hard
考古学者はとても熱心に働いています
He not only went to work in the field
彼はただ畑仕事に行っただけではなく、
After he came back from the field
彼が畑から戻ってきた後
take longer
もっと時間がかかる
to study
勉強する
to analyze
分析します
we can go
私達は行くことができます
from here
ここから
how much to go
どれくらい行きますか
can let us understand a little bit
少しは理解させてもらえますか
Aspects of Ancient Humanity
古代人類の側面
Then the first one is of course
それでは最初のものはもちろん
Do S
ドS
what the hell are we doing
私たちは一体何をしているのですか
what age
どの時代
Now there are many methods
今ではたくさんの方法があります
There are many scientific methods
科学的な手法はたくさんあります
The most commonly used method we call carbon fourteen
最も一般的に使用される方法はカーボン 14 と呼ばれます
In this method, we only need to put the ground inside
この方法では、中に地面を入れるだけです。
Some guerrilla values ​​unearthed
ゲリラ的な価値観の一部が発掘される
Or charcoal sent to the laboratory for analysis
または分析のために木炭を研究所に送る
Finally it can tell us
ついにそれが私たちに伝えられるのです
what is the age of the specimen itself
標本自体の年齢は何年ですか
This is by far the simplest
これが一番簡単です
And one of the most commonly used methods
そして最も一般的に使用される方法の 1 つは
So help us understand the age of
年齢を理解するのに役立ちます
So like we are in Tainan Science Park
まるで台南サイエンスパークにいるようです
we are in different sites
私たちは別のサイトにいる
Different time
違う時間
A chronological sequence can be established
時系列を確立できる
so it's clear
だからそれは明らかです
Each paragraph is clearly
各段落が明確に
these years
ここ数年
There is a lot of chronological data
時系列データがたくさんある
allows us to map the entire region's
地域全体の地図を作成できるようになります
development of the age
時代の発展
can have a clear understanding
明確な理解ができる
At the same time, other methods can be used
同時に他の方法も使用できます
This is what we call stratigraphy
これが層序学と呼ばれるものです
inside the ruins
遺跡の中
can see through layers
地層を通して見ることができる
Types of items that can pass through
通過できるアイテムの種類
after combining the two
2つを組み合わせた後
in a certain layer
ある層で
it may be a certain age
ある程度の年齢かもしれない
This part is also in our archeology
この部分は私たちの考古学でもあります
often used
頻繁に使用されます
a way
あちらへ
Therefore through these methods
したがって、これらの方法を通じて
We can map a region's
地域の地図を作成できます
sequence of its culture
その文化の発展の順序
and some temporal changes in space
そして空間におけるいくつかの時間的変化
can clearly list it
明確にリストアップできる
Like us in Tainan Science Park
台南サイエンスパークの私たちのように
from as early as 5,000 years
5000年前の昔から
Then come up and ask for the big benkeng culture
それから来て、大きなベンケン文化を尋ねてください
Niu Chou Zi Culture
牛仇子文化
Niaosong culture
鳥松文化
Hiraya culture
希拉雅文化
The last Han culture
最後漢人文化
A clear sequence of chronological development
明確な時系列展開
Then each one has a time
それから、それぞれに時間があります
a category
一個範疇
can clearly let us know
はっきりと知らせてくれる
This is all through chronological analysis
これはすべて時系列分析によるものです
established by
によって設立された
In addition, it is very important for us to understand the ancient people
さらに、古代の人々を理解することは私たちにとって非常に重要です
our life
私たちの生活
In life, the people regard time as the sky
人生において、人々は時間を空とみなします
then this one
それからこれ
So we need to understand what ancient people ate
したがって、古代人が何を食べていたのかを理解する必要があります
We also have many methods for this part
この部分にも多くのメソッドがあります
the best way
一番いい方法
We were able to find some evidence directly
いくつかの証拠を直接見つけることができました
or some material
または何らかの資料
Then this can tell us directly
そうすれば、これは私たちに直接伝えることができます
what did he eat
彼は何を食べましたか
Like we are in Tainan Science Park
まるで台南サイエンスパークにいるよう
We found the row above
上の行を見つけました
all this
このすべて
As a look, the top row is
見てみると、一番上の行は、
plant legacy
植物の遺産
what's in the middle of this relic
この遺物には何が入っているのか
There is rice
お米があります
there is millet
キビがあります
melon pit
メロンピット
And this hard worker, etc.
そしてこの頑張り屋さん、などなど。
The remains of these many plants
これらの多くの植物の残骸
these plants left behind
残されたこれらの植物
All why it can be preserved until now
現在まで保存できる理由のすべて
because five thousand years
だって五千年も
it should have rotted away
朽ち果てるべきだった
because of these things
これらのことのせいで
They were all burned by this carbon.
それらはすべてこの炭素によって焼かれました。
carbonized
炭化した
So carbonize this
それでこれを炭化する
after being charred
焦げた後
turned into charcoal
炭になった
so it doesn't perish easily
簡単には滅びないように
So it can still be preserved
だからまだ保存できるんだよ
you see we now find out
わかりますか、今わかります
there are so many of these
これらはたくさんあります
these millets
これらの雑穀
this millet
このキビ
A lot of this 90,000 pieces of millet
このキビ9万枚がたっぷり
This is the first time Taiwan has discovered
台湾で発見されたのは初めて
and a lot of rice stuff
そしてお米もたくさん
are directly reflected
ダイレクトに反映される
At that time, people could already eat these crops.
当時、人々はすでにこれらの作物を食べることができました。
It can eat what it wants, of course it has to grow
食べたいものは食べられる、もちろん成長しなければならない
it has the ability to farm
農業をする能力がある
then like another like this part
次に、この部分のような別の部分のように
There are many kinds of direct longevity bone fish bone
直寿骨魚骨は種類が豊富
These also reflect the food that some people ate at that time
これらは当時の人々が食べていた食べ物も反映しています
Then we will of course do some analysis on these materials
その後、もちろんこれらの材料について分析を行います
do some analysis
分析をする
like this rice
このお米のように
We did analysis like morphology
形態学のような分析をしました
Analysis of these morphology
これらの形態の解析
Just look at its size and shape
その大きさと形を見てください
can be observed
観察できる
An evolution of these rices at different times
さまざまな時代における米の進化
Because rice it will change again
ご飯また変わるから
its breed also changes
品種も変わります
This change in farming techniques
このような農業技術の変化
It will also produce some changes in its species
また、その種にもいくつかの変化が生じるでしょう
So change from its shape
だからその形から変わる
Also learn about a reimplementation of a
の再実装についても学習します。
Morphological development of rice
イネの形態発達
Want to see this is
これを見たいのは
about 4,500 years old
樹齢約4,500年
As the rice at that time looking at it
見ている当時のご飯として
so small particles so small
とても小さな粒子なのでとても小さい
Then this modern we improved
その後、この現代的な改良を加えました
Taichung Taichung No. 9
台中 台中第9
Taichung Taichung No. 10
台中 台中10号
These are the rice in our modern farms
これらは私たちの現代の農場の米です
As you can see its particles are very large
ご覧のとおり、その粒子は非常に大きいです
This represents the different breeds
これはさまざまな品種を表しています
time difference
時差
resulting in different varieties of
その結果、さまざまな種類の
these rice
これらの米
These parts you need to go through our research
これらの部分は当社の調査を行う必要があります
to find out
知るために
In addition, like these animals and plants are also
また、これらの動植物も同様に、
the bones of these animals like all of us
私たち全員と同じように、これらの動物の骨
We all do these analyzes
私たちは皆、こうした分析を行っています
At the same time, for each bone
同時に、骨ごとに
It's not just about identifying its class
カテゴリを特定するだけではありません
And to identify it these animals
そしてそれを識別するためにこれらの動物
the existing environment
既存の環境
this can tell us
これは私たちに言えることです
It wasn't just humans at the time
当時は人間だけではなかった
it eats or exploits these animals
これらの動物を食べたり搾取したりする
It also reflects the climate of the time
当時の気候も反映している
because in what environment
なぜならどのような環境で
what kind of animal does it have
どんな動物がいますか
so this part
それでこの部分
must also be done in detail
も詳細に行う必要があります
analysis of these
これらの分析
In addition, if there is no direct evidence
また、直接的な証拠がない場合には、
These actual archaeological remains can be seen
これらの実際の遺跡を見ることができます
Then we can use many scientific methods
そうすれば、多くの科学的手法を使用できるようになります
This is one of our most commonly used methods
これは最も一般的に使用される方法の 1 つです
That is to say carbon 13 and carbon 14
つまり炭素13と炭素14です。
Analysis of this stable isotope
この安定同位体の分析
Because these different plants
なぜなら、これらの異なる植物は、
So about the carbon thirteen and carbon fourteen isotopes
それでは、炭素 13 と炭素 14 の同位体について説明します。
the constituents of the animal it is in
それが含まれている動物の成分
it is different
違います
so so like this
とてもこのように
Which can be divided into have this
これはどれに分けることができますか
Sorry, there is this C3 plant
申し訳ありませんが、この C3 プラントがあります
C4 plants
C4プラント
and plants in Haikou
海口の植物と
terrestrial freshwater plants
陸上淡水植物
it every animal
それはどの動物も
flora and fauna it's different
動植物は違います
So if we just want to analyze what's left of these animals
これらの動物の残骸を分析したいだけなら
Find the carbon 13 and carbon 14 from inside
内部から炭素 13 と炭素 14 を見つけます
carbon fifteen this
カーボン15これ
The quality of so-called quiet isotopes
いわゆる静かな同位体の品質
let us speculate
推測してみましょう
At that time, he might have eaten a certain kind of
その時、彼はある種のものを食べたのかもしれない
these plants
これらの植物
What is the environment in which it exists?
それが存在する環境は何ですか？
So this is all using the scientific method
つまり、これはすべて科学的手法を使用しているということです
I'm just listing one
一つだけ列挙します
In fact, there are many ways
実際にはたくさんの方法があります
can help us go
私たちが行くのを手伝ってくれる
Even if you find no direct evidence
たとえ直接証拠が見つからなくても
From some circumstantial evidence, you can
いくつかの状況証拠から、次のことがわかります。
Let us understand what ancient people ate
古代人が何を食べていたかを理解しましょう
Then what else is it like where we live?
それでは、私たちが住んでいる場所は他にどのようなものなのでしょうか？
What was the life style of this ancient man?
この古代人のライフスタイルは何でしたか？
What is the form of living
生きる形とは何か
The most direct evidence of this is, of course,
もちろん、これの最も直接的な証拠は、
we are inside the archaeological site
私たちは遺跡の中にいます
You can dig into the houses of ancient people
古代人の家を掘ることができます
we can say what house he lives in
彼がどの家に住んでいるのか言えます
right
右
So if you can't dig the house
それで、もし家を掘ることができないなら
at least you can have some relics
少なくとも遺物は残せるだろう
like our ruins
私たちの廃墟のように
Everyone, look at this one by one
皆さん、これを一つずつ見てください
one by one these little by little
一つずつ、これらを少しずつ
what is this
これは何ですか
This is how the ancient people lived in the house
古代人はこうして家に住んでいた
The holes for the pillars he dug when he made the foundation
基礎を作るときに掘った柱用の穴
So the pillar holes can be spread out in this land
この土地に柱の穴が広がるように
when we dig
私たちが掘るとき
Everyone, be very, very careful
皆さん、本当に十分に気をつけてください
That's why some people say that archeology is so slow
だから考古学は遅いと言う人もいる
we are at the construction site
私たちは建設現場にいます
I'm always behind these weird hands
私はいつもこの奇妙な手の後ろにいる
wait until later
後まで待ってください
to build a house
家を建てる
to open a factory
工場を開くには
we dug very slowly
私たちはとてもゆっくりと掘りました
they will scold
彼らは叱るだろう
how can you be so slow
どうしてそんなに遅いのですか
Actually he doesn't know
実は彼は知らない
we're going to dig this up
これを掘り下げてみましょう
this is very very slow
これはとてもとても遅いです
If you hurry up, you won't be able to see
急ぐと見えなくなるよ
So after digging out
それで掘り出した後は
can be displayed
表示できる
the house at that time
当時の家
About 3000 years ago
約3000年前
one shot house
ワンショットハウス
just let us help
ただ私たちに助けてもらいましょう
let's rebuild
再構築しましょう
The shape of the house at that time
当時の家の形
Also in the middle of each house
それも各家の真ん中に
and these sticks
そしてこれらのスティック
It was the people at that time
それが当時の人たちだった
he may be a family unit
彼は家族の一員かもしれない
after someone died
誰かが死んだ後
buried between this house and the house
この家と家の間に埋葬されている
as look over here
ここを見てください
You see these are all buried here
これらはすべてここに埋もれているのがわかります
this reflects
これは反映しています
At that time the whole settlement
当時の集落全体は
this one by one situation
この一つ一つの状況
In addition, we can get from
さらに、以下から取得できます
the whole comprehensive
全体の包括的な
chair excavation
椅子の発掘
can come to rebuild
再建に来られる
The shape of the whole settlement
集落全体の形状
this is inside a chair
これは椅子の中です
reflected by
によって反映される
These houses and green sticks
これらの家と緑の棒
People are buried in this tomb after they die
人は死ぬとこの墓に埋葬されます
In addition, there is this suffix in the middle, I can't read clearly
また、真ん中にこの接尾辞があり、はっきりと読めません
there are some circle points
いくつかの丸点があります
These movements of houses
こうした家の動き
Stationary moving flow
静止した移動流
Then the ones next to it are darker
すると、その隣の色が暗くなります
It's the garbage dump we're talking about
私たちが話しているのはゴミ捨て場です
is to dump the rubbish where it settles
ゴミは落ち着く場所に捨てることです
We are the same now
今も私たちは同じです
Now our garbage will be thrown next to the village
今、私たちのゴミは村の隣に捨てられます
So this represents a small village at that time
これは当時の小さな村を表しています
Its whole we can excavate through archeology
考古学を通じてそのすべてを発掘することができます
dig out
掘り出す
After this excavation
この発掘の後、
Then of course it directly reflects
もちろんそれは直接反映されます
A living form of people at that time
当時の人々の生きた姿
Another form of settlement
別の決済方法
Then, of course, we will also learn about a settlement.
それから、当然、和解についても学びます。
not only its settlement itself
その集落自体だけでなく
and the relationship between the settlement and the surrounding environment
集落と周辺環境との関係
So we can also go through some theoretical discussions
したがって、いくつかの理論的な議論も行うことができます
Come and learn about this settlement
この集落について学びに来てください
The relationship between the position of the chair and its surroundings
椅子の位置とその周囲の関係
Why does this settlement live here
なぜこの集落がここにあるのか
So what's the special reason for it's
では、その特別な理由は何でしょうか
This settlement will choose this location here
この居住地はここでこの場所を選択します
the various environments around and around
周囲のさまざまな環境
this is the relationship we're talking about
これが私たちが話している関係です
This is also called
これはとも呼ばれます
our participle is called
私たちの分詞は呼ばれます
always giving analysis
常に分析を与える
This is a method of analysis
これは分析方法です
In addition, through some theoretical analysis, we can
さらに、いくつかの理論的分析を通じて、次のことができます。
make use of economic geography
経済地理を利用する
so-called middle ground theory
いわゆる中間点理論
叫Central Place Theory
叫セントラルプレイス理論
this section to learn about these
これらについて学ぶには、このセクションを参照してください
inside this area
このエリア内で
all the different clubs
さまざまなクラブすべて
relationship with each other
お互いの関係
with some of its reflections
その反省の一部を含めて
social meaning
社会的意味
like representing different social structures
さまざまな社会構造を表現するような
a social formation
社会的形成
it will render different
それは異なるものをレンダリングします
These forms of these clubs
これらのクラブのこれらの形式
Another analysis like this social structure
こんな社会構造のような分析も
We understand that there was no society
私たちは社会が存在しなかったことを理解しています
what kind of society
どのような社会なのか
Is it an egalitarian society after all?
結局平等社会なのでしょうか？
or a stratified society
あるいは階層化社会
This society can
この社会ができることは、
archaeological data to understand
理解するための考古学的データ
look like this
このように見える
this is a stick
これは棒です
This stick is actually
実はこのスティック、
it can tell us
それは私たちに伝えることができます
a lot about this
これについてたくさん
training in social structure
社会構造の訓練
like these as seen
見られるようにこれらのように
inside these sticks
この棒の中には
Sorry, sorry, I don't know how to do this yet
ごめんなさい、ごめんなさい、まだやり方がわかりません
So, this one, these lines of recruitment are in the village
つまり、これらの募集ラインは村にあります
then it's inside
それなら中にあるよ
it can get from it's this burial thing
それはこの埋葬物から得られる
Can reflect a social status among people
人々の社会的地位を反映することができる
or a difference in wealth using the difference
あるいはその差を利用した貧富の差
In addition, it is said that some of the funeral objects it buried
また、副葬品の一部は埋葬されたと言われています。
It can also reflect some differences between
また、いくつかの違いを反映することもあります。
So what about this solicitation?
では、この勧誘はどうでしょうか？
It is a reflection of social structure
を反映できる社会構造です。
a very important piece of evidence
非常に重要な証拠
Of course there are many other evidences
もちろん他にも証拠はたくさんある
settlement like this
このような決済
Then this is the site of the Hongshan Culture in the northeast of the mainland
そして、ここは大陸の北東部にある紅山文化の場所です。
It is calculated using mathematical models
数学モデルを使用して計算されます
Look at the closeness of a distance between each settlement
各集落間の距離の近さを見る
then to distinguish
それから区別するために
words like here
ここのような言葉
like this this as see this
これのようにこれを見てください
These are different
これらは異なります
What about this area?
この地域はどうでしょうか？
it can be divided into four pieces
4つの部分に分けることができます
Look at this one, two dollars, three dollars, four dollars
これを見てください、1ドル、2ドル、3ドル、4ドル
Then it is reflected in the highest mathematical model
そしてそれは最上位の数学モデルに反映されます
It is all the settlements, it is more concentrated
それはすべての集落であり、より集中しています
The density of its entire space is very tight
空間全体の密度が非常に高い
Then this thing reflects it
そうすると、これはそれを反映しています
In this area, it is entirely within the social structure
この領域では完全に社会構造の中にあります
it may represent a different meaning
別の意味を表している可能性があります
Maybe it represents Japan, represents a city
たぶんそれは日本を表している、都市を表している
That next to it might represent the countryside, or something more remote.
その隣にあるものは田舎、あるいはもっと遠い場所を表しているのかもしれません。
Then this reflects the whole
次に、これは全体を反映します
It is an urbanized
都市化されたものです
or a hierarchical
または階層的な
such a social form
そういう社会形態
Then this is using this different method
次に、これはこの別の方法を使用しています
We come and go to learn about some settlements of ancient humans
私たちは古代人類の居住地について学ぶために行き来します。
some forms
いくつかのフォーム
Then in addition, like the eleven cylinders in life
さらに、人生における 11 個のシリンダーのように
Like this one is the best of course we are also the best
これが最高であるように、もちろん私たちも最高です
there is direct evidence
直接的な証拠がある
It can be like this is us in Tainan Science Park
ここが台南サイエンスパークにいるようなものかもしれません
found a large number of this visitor
この訪問者を多数見つけました
What is this visitor doing?
この訪問者は何をしているのですか？
like a spinning
回転するように
represent it spinning thread
紡ぐ糸を表現する
It has thread to make clothes from
服を作るための糸が入っています
Represents that the technology of spinning thread already existed at that time
当時すでに糸を紡ぐ技術があったことを示す
But on the other hand, it is also found that
しかしその一方で、次のようなことも判明しました。
as can't see anything
何も見えないので
This is a broken
これは壊れています
this stick
この棒
a stick
棒
Here are the stripes
こちらがストライプです
Someone read it and I said what is this
誰かがそれを読んで、これは何だと言った
He said it's called Husband Beater
彼はそれをハズバンド・ビーターと呼ぶと言った
It's a warrior's stick
それは戦士の杖です
because this can hit
これは当たるかもしれないので
In fact, this is a bat called bark cloth
実はこれ、バーククロスというコウモリなんです
It's made of bark cloth
樹皮布でできています
So this is what was inside our clothes
これが私たちの服の中に入っていたものです
In addition to imitation
模倣に加えて
it also uses bark
樹皮も使用します
make bark cloth
樹皮布を作る
There is also direct evidence of this in archaeological sites.
考古学的遺跡にもこのことの直接的な証拠があります。
these people are called ropes
この人たちはロープと呼ばれます
like this imitated line
この真似したセリフのように
Roll it out like this and become that kind of rope
こうやって伸ばしてあんなロープになるよ
This is inside the archaeological site
ここは遺跡の中にあります
can also occasionally be found
時々見つかることもあります
when expectations are good
期待が良いとき
These can be preserved without rotting away
腐らずに保存できる
So these things are some
これらはいくつかです
about when
いつごろ
Some of the most direct of the time
現時点で最も直接的なもののいくつかは、
some so-called evidence some evidence
いくつかのいわゆる証拠 いくつかの証拠
In addition, of course, like through some decorations on the person itself
さらに、もちろん、その人自体に装飾を施すなどして、
Like this one inside a stick
スティックの中にはこんな感じ
As a look it has a lot of shark teeth
見るからにサメの歯がたくさんある
This thing was a decoration at that time
これは当時の飾り物でした
ornament as look
見た目通りの飾り
After it is strung together, it becomes like this
繋ぎ合わせるとこんな感じになります
An act representing the adornment of everyone at the time
当時の人々の装飾を代表する行為
This is the same
これも同じです
Many utensils are also displayed
食器類も多数展示されております
These things can be used as
これらのものは次のように使用できます
At that time, I learned that it was a form of decoration at that time
その時、それが当時の装飾だったのだと知りました
In addition, the so-called earrings are also stuffed on the ears.
また、いわゆるイヤリングも耳に詰められます。
this is an earring
これはイヤリングです
This is all direct evidence that tells us
これはすべて、私たちに伝える直接的な証拠です。
reflect the clothing of the time
当時の服装を反映している
such a situation
そのような状況
This is what we can base on various evidences
これはさまざまな証拠に基づいてできることです
after putting it back together
元に戻してから
Humans at that time
あの頃の人間は
This was probably around 2000
これはおそらく2000年くらいのこと
What about humans at this time?
このとき人間はどうなるのでしょうか？
he was clumsy
彼は不器用だった
such a situation
そのような状況
In addition, technology
さらに、テクノロジー
We want ancient people how to make things
私たちは古代人に物の作り方を知りたい
Technology
テクノロジー
In fact, there are quite a lot of methods
実は方法はたくさんあります
like making pottery
陶器作りのような
we can use these
これらを使用できます
These features on pottery
陶器のこんな特徴
These morphological features
これらの形態学的特徴は、
also to restore his pottery
彼の陶器を修復するためにも
every step
すべてのステップ
This, of course, requires some analysis
もちろん、これにはある程度の分析が必要です
like the fire of these pottery
この陶器の火のように
and the erection of pottery, etc.
陶器の組み立てなど。
can help us rebuild
私たちの再建を助けてくれる
At that time a technique for making pottery
当時の陶器の技法
In addition, the same is true
また、同様のことが言えます
such a practical
そんな実用的な
what is it for
それはなんのためですか
how it is made
どのように作られるのか
It is also possible to use some experimental methods
いくつかの実験的方法を使用することも可能です
Then we rebuild
それから再構築します
At that time the actual
その時の実際の
its possible use
その可能性のある用途
this is the same
これも同じです
this is a knife
これはナイフです
was used to speculate
推測するために使われていた
probably for cutting
おそらくカット用
to harvest
収穫するため
broken
壊れた
We can experimentally
実験的にはできる
come help us go
来て、私たちが行くのを手伝ってください
through these other analytical methods
これらの他の分析方法を通じて
Include this analysis of utility traces
このユーティリティ トレースの分析を含めます
And on the wind blade of this knife
そしてこのナイフの風刃には
These chemical analyzes of some residues
いくつかの残留物のこれらの化学分析
come help us rebuild
再建を手伝ってください
the knife itself
ナイフ自体
the way it's used
使われ方
function and the technology it makes
機能とそれが生み出す技術
That can also help us to
それは私たちにも役立ちます
archaeological data
考古資料
allows us to understand the ancient
古代人について学びましょう
some doubts about life
人生についてのいくつかの疑問
its life doubt
その人生に対する疑問
people know this person in his lifetime
人々はこの人の生前を知っています
there will be many suspicions
多くの疑惑があるだろう
There are many suspicions of birth, old age, illness and death
出生、老衰、病気、死については多くの疑惑がある
like this from this like this
このように、これから、このように
Most sticks inside
ほとんどのスティックは内部にあります
can understand when a person dies
人がいつ死ぬかを理解できる
how to deal with it
それにどう対処するか
It's a deadly suspicion
それは致命的な疑惑だ
As it looks like this is
このように見えるので
This is probably in
これはおそらく入っています
The 2,500-year-old site
2,500年前の遺跡
above as seen
上に見られるように
This man is buried in it
この男はその中に埋もれている
Next to this is the viewing tree
この隣に展望ツリーがあります
This view has emerged
こういう見方が出てきた
But we can dig through this very carefully
しかし、これを非常に注意深く掘り下げることができます
Can dig out traces of its closing curtain
カーテンが閉まった跡を掘り出すことができる
and then in the man's bones themselves
そしてその人の骨自体の中に
is it lying down
横になっていますか
Barbarians like now are rotten people
今みたいな野蛮人は腐った人です
This is a common custom in this society
これはこの社会では一般的な習慣です
so dirty
とても汚い
In addition to this above
上記に加えて
must be on every roof of it
それのすべての屋根にあるはずです
There must be a clay pot
土鍋もあるはず
There's something in this clay pot
この土鍋の中に何かが入っています
We analyze some food in it
その中に含まれる食品を分析します
like bones chicken bones
鶏の骨のようなもの
fish bones with food
魚の骨と餌
This is an offering
これはお供え物です
a sacrificial
犠牲的な
a sacrificial pottery
犠牲の陶器
above so it must be above the head of its house
上にあるので、家の頭の上にあるはずです
will put this sacrifice
この犠牲を捧げます
So this is one of the society at that time
これが当時の社会の一つです
a common burial a custom
一般的な埋葬
a ritual habit
儀式的な習慣
Well so this is where we get back together
さて、ここが私たちが再び集まる場所です
At that time, it was probably a kind of burial, a sacrificial ritual
当時、それはおそらく一種の埋葬、犠牲の儀式でした。
that additionally acts as
さらに次のように機能します
Everyone look at this
みんなこれ見て
This is a human skeleton of a woman
これは女性の人骨です
You see it between the legs
脚の間に見えます
and a baby
そして赤ちゃん
Have you seen
見たことがありますか
This looks like it will be very impressive
これはとても印象に残りそうですね
because of what
何かのせいで
because of this person
この人のせいで
This woman may have had a difficult labor during labor
この女性は出産中に難産だった可能性がある
Both mother and child were disturbed after she was born
出産後は母子ともに不安を抱えていた
it's all passed away
それはすべて過ぎ去った
so when she buried
それで彼女が埋葬したとき
And put her little one in mother's
そして、彼女の小さな子供を母親のところに置きました
the middle of the thigh
太ももの真ん中
this child
この子
This thing is through our archeology
これは私たちの考古学によるものです
very careful excavation
非常に慎重な発掘
To be able to find this phenomenon
この現象を発見できるようにするには
able to dig out
掘ることができる
also reflected
也反映出来
At that time, there was something about death in this society.
当時、この社会には死が存在していました。
a treat for this matter
このことへのご褒美
like in this amusement society
この娯楽社会のように
A child is not treated as a person at all
子供はまったく人間として扱われていない
So just throw it away after you die
だから死んだら捨てればいい
eaten by dogs
犬に食べられる
But in this society
でもこの社会では
we got from another ranch
他の牧場からもらいました
He has always had great respect for children
彼はいつも子供たちに大きな敬意を払ってきた
also very good
とても良い
Even if he is a small child
たとえ彼が小さな子供であっても
It also covers him very well.
それはまた彼を非常によくカバーします。
Also like this man his teeth
この人の歯も好きです
This is the same as Han Xi's Taiwanese aborigines
これは韓熙の台湾原住民と同じだ
There is such a custom of tooth extraction
こんな抜歯の習慣もあるんですね
We know tooth extraction is a ritual
私たちは抜歯が儀式であることを知っています
like many adults in aboriginal
アボリジニの多くの大人と同じように
Or one that he has military exploits
あるいは武功があるとか
he may perform some kind of ceremony
彼は何らかの儀式を執り行うかもしれない
Pulling out his front teeth
前歯を抜く
Second incisor Lateral incisor
第二切歯側切歯
His teeth were pulled out
彼の歯は抜かれた
Such a custom is present in our aboriginal society
私たちの先住民社会にはそのような習慣が存在します
In the past, there were still many tribes
昔はまだたくさんの部族がいた
There is also the custom of tooth extraction
抜歯の習慣もある
This can be found in the pastoral chapter
これは司牧の章にあります
can let us understand the life at that time
当時の生活を理解させてもらえますか
A manifestation of life I
生命の現れ I
In addition, what we just talked about
さらに、今お話ししたことは、
It's all material
それはすべて材料です
In fact, it is spiritual
実はそれは精神的なもので、
We can pass through many material first-class
多くの素材を一級品として通過することができます
The same can help us to
同じことが私たちにも役立ちます
Restoring the manpower of the past
かつての人材を取り戻す
some leading states
いくつかの主要な州
Like this from many artifacts
たくさんのアーティファクトの中からこんな感じ
We can learn about its cognitive
その認知機能について学ぶことができます
in this respect as it does for aesthetics
この点でも美学と同様に
for aesthetic
美観のために
such a cognition
そういう認識
In addition, some religious beliefs and so on are reflected
また、一部宗教上の信仰などが反映されております。
In fact, many can still be obtained from material
実際、多くはまだ材料から入手できます
Come and help us to rebuild
復興に協力しに来てください
guys look like this
みんなこんな感じ
This is what was unearthed inside our chair
これは私たちの椅子の中から発掘されたものです
These images of these faces
これらの顔のこれらの画像
Everyone, look at this, it's very cute
皆さん見てください、とても可愛いですよ
It's kind of like ET's
ETみたいな感じですね
like space
宇宙のような
look like a man from outer space
宇宙から来た人間のように見える
I don't know if they've seen aliens
彼らが宇宙人を見たことがあるかどうかはわかりません
But this is the Model it made
しかし、これは彼らが作ったモデルです
actually very much like
実際にとても似ています
like this one from ET
ETのこれのように
like this is
これのように
then this is a
それならこれは
it seems we often talk
私たちはよく話しているようです
This looks a bit like an Indian
ちょっとインド人っぽいですね
Everyone look at this high nose
みんな見てこの高い鼻
this hair
この髪
like a foreigner now
もう外国人みたい
So this representative was the person at the time
この代表が当時の人だったんですね
his kind of difference between you and me
あなたと私の違いは彼のようなもの
he saw these people look
彼は彼らがこうしているのを見た
make him different
彼を違うものにする
So he made a performance in the cognition of a group of people
そこで彼は人々のグループの認識においてパフォーマンスを行った
There is also a lot of information on these
こういった情報もたくさんあります
like this tomb staff
この墓のスタッフのように
in the whole society
社会全体で
in burial customs
埋葬習慣の中で
its cognition
その認識
All avatars must face in one direction
すべてのアバターは一方向を向いていなければなりません
This picture is from the north
この写真は北側から撮ったものです
everyone look north
みんな北を見ます
will face north
北を向くでしょう
in other cultures
他の文化では
all facing south
すべて南向き
Facing south
南向き
This reflects the beliefs of the time
これは当時の信仰を反映しています
maybe
多分
like they are now muslim
彼らは今イスラム教徒であるかのように
this islam
このイスラム教
So all of his people are headed towards Mai's house
それで彼の仲間全員が麻衣の家に向かっている
The manifestation of such a concept
そんなコンセプトの具現化
In addition, of course the substance
また、物質はもちろん、
There are many transactions
取引件数が多い
So we are in this will
だから私たちはこの意志の中にいます
Lots of items to trade can be found
取引できるアイテムがたくさん見つかる
not natively generated
ネイティブに生成されていない
it reflects a transaction
トランザクションを反映します
This deal has a short distance deal
この取引には短距離取引があります
or long-distance transactions
または長距離取引
able to come from far away
遠くから来られる
or available nearby
または近くで利用可能
These things are a
これらのことは、
human interaction
人的交流
an act of trading
取引行為
Therefore, through the analysis of these materials
そこで、これらの材料を分析することで、
Materials like these can be analyzed from its raw material
このような材料は原料から分析できます
Analysis from its place of origin
原点から分析
to understand the possible sources of these things
これらのものの考えられる原因を理解する
And the behavior of a transaction that may represent behind it
そして、その背後にある可能性のあるトランザクションの動作
this part
この部分
You can see that this is about a thousand years ago in Taiwan
これは約1000年前の台湾のものであることがわかります
These ancient humans in Taiwan had a lot of transactions with these Han people
台湾の古代人類は漢民族と多くの交流を持っていました
Just saw these magnets
これらの磁石を見たところです
these peachy
これらの桃っぽい
these brass and so on
この真鍮など
It was all obtained through a kind of exchange between the Han people
それはすべて漢民族間の一種の交流を通じて得られたものです
In addition, you can also learn about the behavior of ancient humans in war.
さらに、戦争における古代人類の行動についても学ぶことができます。
let's watch
見よう
The most direct evidence of this is that we can get
このことの最も直接的な証拠は、
Pay attention to this sentence, human bones
この文に注目してください、人骨
It looks pretty pitiful at first
最初はかなり可哀想に見えます
so it's on
それでオンです
this is this look at this thing
これはこれです、これを見てください
it's an archery arrow
それはアーチェリーの矢です
arrow
矢印
These arrows shot under this leash of it
この矢はこの鎖の下で射られた
In addition, it also had a kind of wound on its lumbar spine
さらに、腰椎にも傷のようなものがあった
Then he was hit by an arrow on the hand bone of the lower limb bone of this hand
そして彼はこの手の下肢の骨に矢が当たった
So he has an arrow in his waist
だから彼の腰には矢が刺さっている
so he got hit by several arrows
それで彼は何本かの矢に当たった
This represented a conflicting behavior at the time
これは当時矛盾した行動を表していました
Of course in ancient times these wars
もちろん古代にはこうした戦争があった
In fact, he may not really be a war
実際のところ、彼は本当に戦争をする人ではないかもしれません
some are rituals
いくつかは儀式です
like this beheading thing
この斬首事件のように
In fact, he must represent
実際、彼は代表しなければなりません
So it must be a conflict between the two ethnic groups
つまり、それは二つの民族グループ間の紛争に違いない
He sometimes represents a ritual
彼は時々儀式を表します
Beheading like this represents being in a society
このような斬首は社会に参加していることを意味します
he has a special ritual
彼には特別な儀式がある
a meaning
意味
like this guy too
この人もそうだよ
As a look at him too
彼を見てみると、
There's a suspicious arrow here
ここに怪しい矢印があります
Here the head was chopped off
ここで首が切り落とされた
This head is gone
この頭がなくなってしまった
head cut off
首を切り落とされた
Then this hand shot an arrow here
そしてこの手はここに矢を放った
There is an arrow here
ここに矢印があります
Have you seen
見たことがありますか
the head is missing
頭が欠けている
This represents a kind of
これはある種のことを表します
conflict or war
紛争または戦争
But we are in Taiwan
しかし、私たちは台湾にいます
I have been doing archaeology for so long
私は長い間考古学をやっています
tell the truth
本当のことを言え
Our Ancient Ancestors in Taiwan
台湾の古代の祖先
he is very peaceful
彼はとても平和です
We did not find any
何も見つかりませんでした
This situation of mass killing
この大量殺戮の状況
Occasionally, one or two things like this are found
時々、このようなものが1つまたは2つ見つかります
This body was beheaded
この遺体は斬首された
Or just one or two
それとも1つか2つだけ
We have not found such a million species
これほど100万種も見つかったことはありません
Or the situation of mass killings
あるいは大量殺人の状況
Basically it's pretty peaceful
基本的にはとても平和です
such a society
そんな社会
Everyone saw this just now
みんな今これ見たよ
This is what we round up
これが私たちがまとめたものです
probably it's here
おそらくここにあります
this is from the front
これは正面からです
from the tip of the shot
ショットの先端から
This is the sign shot from behind
後ろから撮った看板です
or an arrow shot it to death
あるいは矢で射殺された
Then cut off the head
それから首を切り落とします
cut off the head
頭を切り落とす
wrap hands
手を包む
In addition, for these diseases of ancient people
また、古代人のこれらの病気に対しては、
physical condition can also be
体調不良も考えられます
These archaeological data to explain
説明するためのこれらの考古学的データ
like this through this person
この人を通してこうやって
We can understand the symptoms of many diseases
多くの病気の症状を理解できる
like the most common
最も一般的なもののように
Easiest to see is dental disease
一番分かりやすいのは歯の病気です
everybody look
みんな見て
This is also dental disease
これも歯の病気です
The one here is called Nongyang
ここは農陽と呼ばれるものです
Its tooth root can run this way
歯の根はこのように走ることができます
see it doesn't
見てください、そうではありません
Then of course cast teeth
それからもちろん鋳造歯
this is the most common
これが最も一般的です
this asian disease
このアジアの病気
This is the most common disease
これは最も一般的な病気です
Also like here
こちらもいいね
There's a tumor here
ここに腫瘍があります
This man has a large tumor on his head
この男性の頭には大きな腫瘍がある
The other most common is this
他に最も一般的なのはこれです
Herniation of this vertebral disc
この椎間板ヘルニア
like this
このような
we talk about this
私たちはこれについて話します
We usually talk about bone spurs
私たちはいつも骨棘について話します
In addition to the bone itself
骨そのものに加えて
these anemias
これらの貧血
This nutritional deficiency and so on
この栄養不足などで
can pass through these human bones
この人間の骨を通り抜けることができます
to understand
理解する
This also reflects
これも反映してる
Not just the state of human health at the time
当時の人間の健康状態だけではなく
It also reflects the nutritional status of the
栄養状態も反映します
It also reflects the environmental conditions at that time
その時の環境条件も反映されます
some things about many, many ancient people
非常に多くの古代の人々についてのいくつかのこと
so these
それでこれら
so this aspect
したがって、この側面
there are many
沢山あります
provide us with an understanding of ancient humans'
古代人類についての理解をもたらしてくれる
a lot of these
これらの多くの
these about health
健康に関するこれら
environment nutrition
環境栄養
and its labor
そしてその労力
Some are too tired
疲れすぎている人もいる
will also be left on the body
体にも残ります
many of these traces
これらの痕跡の多くは
so this part
それでこの部分
can also
こともできます
These are very precious materials
とても貴重な資料です
can now also understand
今も理解できる
Did Ancient People Have Lung Disease?
古代人には肺疾患があったのでしょうか?
TB
結核
punch the bone
骨を殴る
You can also learn about infectious diseases, etc.
感染症などについても学ぶことができます。
in addition
加えて
Finally we want to understand
最後に私たちは理解したいのです
what do you want to look like
あなたはどのように見えたいですか
what does it look like
それは何に見えますか
Now we also have many ways
今では私たちにもたくさんの方法があります
The most traditional method now
現在最も伝統的な方法
Just use these human bones
この人骨を使ってください
We can see us as human bones
私たちは人間の骨として見ることができます
we can
我々はできる
find a human skull
人間の頭蓋骨を見つける
We can now take advantage of advanced equipment
先進的な設備を活用できるようになりました
This is 3D scanning
これは3Dスキャンです
ready to print
印刷準備完了
So 3D printing
そこで3Dプリント
can take this man to the bone
この男を骨の髄まで引き取ることができる
can print it out
印刷できます
become like this
こうなる
a mold comes out
型が出てくる
Then put this mold
次にこの型を入れます
and then remolding
そして再成型
turned into a
に変わった
A rice in a mold inside
中には型に入ったお米が入っています
Then above this we pass through
次に、この上を通過します
This so-called muscle filling
このいわゆる筋肉の充填
This muscle filling is not random filling
この筋肉の充填はランダムな充填ではありません
must be based on a lot of data
多くのデータに基づいている必要があります
Through anatomical data
解剖学的データを通じて
to learn about different races
さまざまな人種について学ぶ
the probable thickness of its muscles
推定される筋肉の厚さ
and muscle growth
そして筋肉の成長
Then according to this thing
それからこの事によると
Let's do some muscle filling
筋肉を補いましょう
Finally we can have some
ついに食べられるようになりました
archaeological art
考古学芸術
This person is here to help us
この人は私たちを助けるためにここにいます
to restore
復元する
contains its hair
その毛が含まれています
hair eyebrows
髪の眉毛
whole face etc.
顔全体など
to restore
復元する
This is in our Tantan Science Park
ここはたんたんサイエンスパーク内です
A skull from about 5,000 years ago
約5000年前の頭蓋骨
Finally we based on these skulls
最後に、これらの頭蓋骨に基づいて
can be recovered
回復できる
A face of the possible length at that time
その時の可能な長さの顔
what kind of thing
どのようなものですか
so we do quite a bit
だから私たちはかなりのことをします
We can be in different times
私たちは異なる時代にいることもできる
These human bones of us in different times
さまざまな時代の私たちの人骨
Finally recovered
ようやく回復しました
This was about a thousand years ago
これは約千年前のことです
Ancient humans in Taiwan
台湾の古代人
You see, she looks a little prettier
ほら、彼女は少し可愛く見えるよ
this is a female
これは女性です
these a male
これらは男性です
Well, this is when they
さて、これは彼らが
after death
死後
Human bones look like this
人間の骨はこんな感じ
This is also through some scientific methods
これもいくつかの科学的手法によるものです
restore it
それを復元する
now there is another way
今は別の方法があります
computer simulation, etc.
コンピューターシミュレーションなど
to restore the face of ancient people
古代人の顔を復元する
a look
一見
Then finally we can put all
そして最後にすべてを入れることができます
Eleven aspects of these materials are annotated
これらの資料の 11 の側面に注釈が付けられています
war its society and more
戦争、社会など
can put the whole time
ずっと置くことができます
the face of human life
人間の人生の顔
to do a comprehensive
包括的なことをする
such a recovery
そんな回復
so in addition
じゃあ他には？
That is, we can also understand the human environment at that time
つまり、当時の人間環境もわかるのです
What was the living environment like at that time?
当時の生活環境はどのようなものでしたか？
This we can use through
これを介して使用できます
Analysis of Soil by Valley
谷別の土壌分析
The strict detective of the earth's core and so on
地球の核の厳格な探偵など
to do these analyzes
これらの分析を行うには
But it's impossible for me to go into detail here
しかし、ここでは詳細には触れられません
Then this part can come and let us rebuild
それからこの部分が来て、再構築しましょう
The environments that humans faced at that time
当時の人類が直面していた環境
Of course, this environment can also include the
もちろん、この環境には、
Through animal legacy, plant legacy, etc.
動物の遺産、植物の遺産などを通じて
to tell us about the circumstances
状況を私たちに伝えるために
like the weather
天気のように
but what about the season
でも季節はどうだろう
and the nearby surrounding landforms at that time
当時の付近の地形と
what is the terrain like
地形はどんな感じですか
can help us recover
私たちの回復を助けることができる
Then this is in our solar science park
それから、これは私たちの太陽科学パーク内です
Through this extended new expert
この拡張された新しい専門家を通じて
Taking Soil Analysis
土壌分析を受ける
we can come back
私たちは戻ってくることができます
The location of Nanke at that time
当時の南柯の位置
In fact, where was the scope at that time?
実際、当時の範囲はどこにあったのでしょうか？
here is the sea
ここは海です
At that time the settlement has been here
そのとき和解はここにありました
it's all by the sea
それはすべて海沿いです
there are people who live by the sea
海の近くに住んでいる人がいる
This is right next to the beach for living
ここはビーチのすぐ隣にあります
But now you can see
でも今ならわかるよ
As a mainlander from Tainan, you know
台南出身の本土人ならご存知でしょう。
This is Qigu
キグです
Currently at the beach
現在ビーチにいます
Now Nanke's work is in the sea
今、南柯氏の作品は海にあります
in sea field
海のフィールドで
It's 20 kilometers away
20キロ離れています
time difference of 5000 years
5000年の時差
The sea was still here in 5000 years
海は5000年後もここにあった
around here in about 3000
3000年頃にこのあたりで
now the beach
今はビーチ
the coast is here too
海岸もここにあります
Qigu
キグ
Yantian on Qigu's side is here
Qigu側のYantianがここにいます
So the distance between them is more than 20 kilometers
つまり、彼らの間の距離は20キロ以上あります
So we talk about sea fields
そこで、シーフィールドについて話します
But this can be found through our archaeological research
しかし、これは私たちの考古学調査を通じて発見できます
You can also do something based on the environment at that time
その時の環境に合わせて何かをすることもできます
these endowments
これらの寄付金
In addition, of course we have to understand a culture
さらに、もちろん文化を理解する必要があります
Ancients and his relationship
古代人とその関係
what is his source
彼の情報源は何ですか
where did he come from
彼はどこから来たのですか
This part is inside archeology
この部分は考古学の範囲内です
It is also possible to use these typological comparisons
これらの類型比較を使用することもできます。
The ratio angle of these vapors
これらの蒸気の比角
Now through the comparison of the DNA of the crowd
群衆の DNA を比較してみましょう
There are also animals raised in living things, etc.
生き物などで飼育されている動物もいます。
You can come to know the source of these people
あなたはこれらの人々の源を知ることができます
where the hell
一体どこに
This is in Tainan Academy of Sciences area
ここは台南科学院エリアにあります
5000 years ago
5000年前的
This human speculates about his origin
この人間は自分の出自について推測している
After comparing these analyzes
これらの分析を比較した後、
His source is from
彼の情報源は、
Probably from south of Fujian to Hainan Island
おそらく福建省南部から海南島まで
up this coast
この海岸の上まで
It is probably between the culture of Taiwan 5,000 years ago
おそらく5000年前の台湾の文化の間
very close relationship
非常に親密な関係
their source
彼らの情報源
Their home probably came from this place
彼らの家はおそらくこの場所から来たのでしょう
This can also be told through these data
このことは、これらのデータからもわかります
In addition, the relationship between people
また、人と人との関係は、
In addition to the typological comparison on this artifact
このアーティファクトの類型学的比較に加えて、
Now this is also
さて、これも
The so-called genetic analysis and comparison of this ethnic group
この民族グループのいわゆる遺伝子分析と比較
then this aspect
それからこの側面
We've actually done a lot so far
私たちはこれまで本当にたくさんのことをしてきました
That's us in Nanke
それが南渓の私たちです
This is a site of the Three Treasures
ここは三宝のサイトです
DNA extracted from his bones
彼の骨から抽出されたDNA
come to know these people
この人たちを知るようになる
where he may have been a source
彼が情報源だったかもしれない場所
and genetic relationships with other populations
他の集団との遺伝的関係
In addition, through these human bones themselves,
また、この人骨そのものを通じて、
Some of his measured features
彼の測定された特徴のいくつか
Some measured features can also be used to understand the relationship between each other
一部の測定された特徴は、互いの関係を理解するために使用することもできます。
So this aspect is also very important in archaeology.
したがって、この側面は考古学でも非常に重要です。
To understand the relationship between people and people
人と人との関係を理解する
This is a very important means
これはとても重要な手段です
this is what we do
これが私たちがやっていることです
Our knowledge quiz in January
1月の知識クイズ
Professor Chen Zhongyu's work on guiding people
人々を導く陳中宇教授の取り組み
This is the Marx Planck Institute in Germany
これを使用しているのはドイツのマルクス・プランク研究所です
The DNA they made out of the Quantitative Humans
彼らが定量的な人間から作った DNA
genetic analysis
遺伝子解析
Discover the haploids inside
内部の一倍体を発見
The so-called 10,000 haploid
いわゆる10,000一倍体
its distribution throughout the region
地域全体への分布
This can also give us some clues
これもいくつかの手がかりを与える可能性があります
movement of these people
この人たちの動き
direction of movement
移動方向
source of movement etc.
動きの源など
so
それで
Mainly to introduce to you
主に皆さんにご紹介するのが
How Archeology Gets Closer to the Ancients
考古学はどのようにして古代人に近づくのか
It's easy for us modern people
私たち現代人にとっては簡単なことですが、
meet every day
毎日会う
But the ancient people actually
でも、実は古代の人たちは、
Must go through these archaeological crowns
これらの考古学的王冠を通過しなければなりません
Among the data unearthed
発掘されたデータの中には
then bit by bit
それから少しずつ
Through these clues
これらの手がかりを通して
Let's turn the life of ancient human beings into
古代人類の生活を変えてみよう
slowly piece it together
ゆっくりとつなぎ合わせて
How much can we finally know
最終的にどこまで知ることができるか
What was the condition of the ancient people?
古代人の状態はどうだったのでしょうか？
Of course he won't stand up and argue to me
もちろん彼は立ち上がって私に反論するつもりはありません
He won't stand up and say you're wrong
彼は立ち上がって、あなたが間違っているとは言わないだろう
But I guess it's all archeology itself
しかし、それはすべて考古学そのものだと思います
He must be a scientific
彼は科学者に違いない
what he made
彼が作ったもの
Must conform to some scientific principles
いくつかの科学原則に準拠する必要がある
some level of science
ある程度の科学
Then like this
それからこのように
Then I think the ancients
そうすると古代人はこう思う
Even if he is lying on the ground
たとえ彼が地面に横たわっていても
He won't come to protest
彼は抗議しに来ないだろう
Then the following because of the relationship of time
それでは時間の関係で以下
so I
だから私は
Now I'm going to put some of what we've put together
では、まとめたものをいくつか載せていきます
Let me tell a few stories about ancient people
古代の人々についての話をいくつかさせてください
this story
この話
Then this is what we do in so many archaeological works
それから、これは私たちが非常に多くの考古学的研究で行っていることです
I just picked a few out
いくつか抜粋しただけです
Maybe you are more interested
もしかしたらもっと興味があるかもしれません
or more concerned
またはそれ以上の懸念
Let me give you a brief report
簡単にご報告させていただきます
The first one is the legend of the black ditch
まずは黒い溝の伝説
We know the Black Ditch, everyone knows
私たちはブラック・ディッチを知っています、誰もが知っています
This one is the Penghu Trench
これが澎湖海溝です
This is between Penghu and Taiwan
ここは澎湖と台湾の間です
Probably from this part of Penghu
おそらく澎湖のこの地域から
To the south until the waters of southern Taiwan
南へ、台湾南部海域まで
There is a strong, diffuse sea
強くて拡散した海がある
The sea water depth is about 60 meters to about 100 meters
海水深は約60メートルから約100メートル
such a depth
そんな深さ
very famous recently
最近非常有名
I just told our vice president
私はちょうど副社長に言ったところです
One day news in Taiwan
台湾のある日のニュース
then it's gone
それから消えた
But there is a lot of news abroad
でも海外ではニュースが多いですね
famous foreign magazines
海外の有名雑誌
There are many journals that are still being discussed
まだ議論中の雑誌がたくさんあります
I also saw a Filipino magazine yesterday
昨日もフィリピンの雑誌を見ました
still discussing this issue
この問題についてはまだ議論しています
This was here a few days ago
ここは数日前にここにあった
Probably a few weeks ago
おそらく数週間前
The Department of Natural Sciences in Taichung
台中の自然科学部
Dr. Zhang Junxiang in the museum
博物館にいる張俊祥博士
He did a press conference to publish
彼は出版に向けて記者会見を行った
Said they were in the waters of Penghu
彼らは澎湖の海域にいると述べた
one of the found
見つかったものの一つ
This is the so-called Xia Hangu
これがいわゆる夏漢谷です。
This is the jaw
これが顎です
jaw of a man's jaw ancient
男の顎 古代
Well, everyone, look at Chin Bagu
さあ、皆さん、チンバグを見てください。
it's very primitive
それはとても原始的です
Can't see
見えない
words like ours
私たちのような言葉
Our current people are relatively slender
現在の人々は比較的細身です
Do you see this?
これが見えますか？
it's very out of shape
とても形が崩れています
And the whole assault was very obvious
そして攻撃全体は非常に明白でした
because of its teeth
その歯のせいで
Everyone looks very big
みんなすごく大きく見えます
this is its old tooth
これはその古い歯です
this is very big
これはとても大きいです
then grind hard
それから激しく研ぎます
Then such a lower Russian ancient
それから、そのような下層ロシアの古代
Then Dr. Zhang Junxiang
それから張俊祥博士
then he speculates
それから彼は推測する
His age should be around 190,000 years
彼の年齢は約19万歳であるはずです
to 450,000 years
45万年まで
Of course his age
もちろん彼の年齢は
not quite sure yet
まだよくわかりません
because he is using this
彼がこれを使っているから
Human Lower Russian
人間の下ロシア人
Buddha contained in the upper
上部に仏様が入っています
Buddha and that
仏様とそれ
its two elemental composition
2つの要素の構成
Then Bijiao is in the same sea area
それなら碧角も同じ海域にある
unearthed hound's
発掘された猟犬
a sea duck
シーアヒル
It's on the Hound
ハウンドに載ってるよ
its relative angle
その相対角度
two almost similar branches
ほぼ同じような 2 つの枝
Then this hunting dog is probably in East Asia
となると、この猟犬はおそらく東アジアにいるのでしょう。
the age of its existence
その存在の年齢
should probably exist in
おそらく存在するはずです
About 300,000 to 400,000 years
約30万年から40万年
will probably disappear in the future
おそらく将来的には消えるでしょう
So the evidence thus becomes the inference
したがって、証拠は推論になります
This one is from Lower Russia
これは下ロシア産です
evidence of its age
その年齢の証拠
So Dr. Zhang also infers that this age is 190,000 years
したがって、張博士は、この年齢は19万年であると推測しています
that's all
以上
About 450,000 years or less
約45万年以内
such an age
そんな年齢
Of course we don't care now
もちろん今は気にしない
regardless of this
これとは関係なく
Is the age correct?
年齢は正しいですか？
Then this lower Russia
それからこの下のロシア
Of course, from its shape
もちろんその形状からして
it is a very
それはとてもです
ancient
古代
very primitive of a human
非常に原始的な人間
That's why Dr. Zhang Junxiang called it a Bloomberg Yuanren
張俊祥博士がこれをブルームバーグ原連と呼んだのはこのためです
So he thinks that this person's closest relative is in Anhui in the mainland
そこで彼は、この人物の最も近い親戚が本土の安徽省にいるのではないかと考えています。
Anhui Youming and Xianyuan people
安徽省の陽明と仙源の人々
This is in the range of 500,000 to 300,000 years for the Xianyuan people
これは、仙元族の場合は 50 万年から 30 万年の範囲です。
So he thinks there is a relationship between the two
それで彼はこの2つの間には関係があると考えている
So of course it caused a lot of discussion after it was published.
もちろん、出版後は多くの議論を引き起こしました。
Especially in some foreign publications in this anthropological field
特にこの人類学分野の一部の海外出版物では
There is a lot of discussion on this
これについては多くの議論が行われています
Some people think it's too early
まだ早いと思う人もいる
It's too early because it's unlikely
可能性が低いので時期尚早です
Why? Because in this East Asian region
なぜでしょうか? なぜなら、この東アジア地域では
Especially in Southeast Asia
特に東南アジアでは
Now on an island called Floris in Indonesia
今はインドネシアのフロリス島にいます
The remains of a so-called very primitive human were also found
いわゆる非常に原始的な人類の遺体も発見された
Then his age is 18,000 years
すると彼の年齢は1万8000歳
so their their this
だから彼らのこれは
this man is very small
この人はとても小さいです
so is a very small one
それは非常に小さいものです
a so-called Homo erectus
いわゆるホモ・エレクトス
So the original person is such a
本来の人はそういう人なので、
So what is the relationship between
では、中間の関係とは何でしょうか？
Therefore, further discussion is required
したがって、さらなる議論が必要である
Then this is Wazuhara
それでは和津原です。
This is the Hexian original man found in Hexian, Anhui
これは安徽省の和県で発見された和県の原人です。
So Dr. Zhang Junxiang put the lower frontal bone
そこで張俊祥医師は、前頭骨下部を移植しました。
with this person
この人と
So I think it's the same related two people
なので同じ関係の二人だと思います
He thinks it was probably during the Ice Age
おそらく氷河期の頃だったと彼は考えている
at that time
その時
it's cold
寒いです
in the ice age
氷河期に
Humans moved from north to south to a warmer place
人類は北から南へ暖かい場所へ移動しました
Taiwan's Penghu area
台湾の澎湖地域
It should be relatively warm
比較的暖かいはずです
so hard to run
走るのがとても難しい
so this person
それでこの人
He has remained in this place
彼はこの場所に残っています
keep his original shape, a state
元の形、状態を維持する
Then this is the so-called Penghu Haidu
これがいわゆる澎湖海都です
between Penghu and Taiwan
澎湖と台湾の間
Then this Dr. Zhang Junxiang
それからこの張俊祥博士。
Dr. Lilac said that this specimen came from this trench
ライラック博士は、この標本はこの溝から来たと言いました
And then this specimen was actually supposedly picked up by a fisherman
そして、この標本は実際に漁師によって拾われたとされています
fisherman salvaged
漁師が引き揚げた
Later it was sold to a shareholder
その後株主に売却されました
Then what about their science center?
では、彼らの科学センターはどうなるのでしょうか？
I asked him to buy it from the shareholder again.
もう一度株主から買ってもらいました。
I thought it was important so I bought it
大事なことなので購入しました。
So this is not a scientific discovery
つまり、これは科学的な発見ではありません
or scientific research
または科学研究
It is basically a point and a
それは基本的にポイントであり、その後
a second hand an acquired
中古品
such a data
そのようなデータ
Well, this is the so-called Taiwan Strait
さて、ここはいわゆる台湾海峡です
What about looking at the Taiwan Strait?
台湾海峡を見てみるとどうでしょうか？
This was about 18,000 years ago
これは約18,000年前のことです
It's basically land here.
ここは基本的に陸地です。
We know that after 18,000 years
18,000年後、私たちはそれを知っています
Eighteen thousand years from now, the Ice Banner will end
今からわずか 18,000 年後にアイスバナーは終わる
after the end
終了後
Then the sea level slowly rises
その後、海面はゆっくりと上昇します
so until now
だから今まで
we become the taiwan strait
私たちは台湾海峡になります
But eighteen thousand years ago
しかし一万八千年前
This is basically the situation here
基本的にはこのような状況です
This is still a situation next to a continent
これはまだ大陸に隣接した状況です
So this just said this
それで、これはこれを言っただけです
The origin of Penghu is located in
澎湖県の発祥の地は、
In the sea area, apart from the Penghe injustice just mentioned
海域においては、先ほどの彭河不正以外にも、
In fact, a large number of these large non-human fossils have been found in the past
実際、これらの巨大な非人類化石は過去に多数発見されています。
Most of these fossils are fishermen
これらの化石のほとんどは漁師のものです
Because this sea area is very deep, about 60 meters, 90 meters to 120 meters
この海域は非常に深いため、水深約60メートル、90メートルから120メートルまで
This is very deep, generally like our underwater archaeology
これは非常に奥深く、一般的に私たちの水中考古学と同じです
we can't go down this deep
私たちはこれほど深くは行けません
So a lot of fishermen get off their net
それで多くの漁師が網から降りる
After getting off the net, except for a lot of live fish jumping around
網から降りた後、たくさんの生きた魚が飛び跳ねている以外は
There are a lot of things that can't jump, these big things
ジャンプできないものがたくさんある、大きなものは
So the local fishermen are scared
だから地元の漁師たちは怖がっている
At first, I was very scared and felt that there was a bad omen.
最初はとても怖くて、何か不吉な予感がするような気がしました。
So there are some throwing there and putting it next to the temple and throwing it there
それで、そこに投げたり、寺院の隣に置いて、そこに投げたりすることもあります
dare not ask him
あえて彼に尋ねないでください
Later, after some of these antiquities dealers or fossil collectors discovered
その後、これらの古遺物ディーラーや化石収集家の一部が発見した後、
I think this is a treasure, so I started to collect this thing
これはお宝だと思うので集め始めました
So now become a water boat
だから今は水上ボートになる
So it becomes very valuable
なのでとても貴重なものになります
So now many fishermen are constantly
そのため、今では多くの漁師が常に
You can also find it while fishing
釣り中にも見つかる
This is a captain named Hong in Penghu
こちらは澎湖のホンという船長です
one of his boats
彼のボートの一隻
He often fishes in the sea
彼はよく海で釣りをします
He often gets these
彼はよくこれらを手に入れます
These things that used to be considered bad omens
かつては悪い予兆と考えられていたこれらのこと
Now he's a baby
今、彼は赤ちゃんです
So a whole warehouse in his house
彼の家の倉庫全体が
all of these
これらすべて
as look
見ての通り
as see this is he fishing
見てください、これは彼が釣りをしているところです
he can fish
彼は魚を釣ることができる
A lot of fun
とても楽しいこと
he fished
彼は釣りをした
catch a bone
骨を捕まえる
not a fish
魚ではありません
But he also caught a fish
でも彼も魚を捕まえた
This is the archeology of water effect that we did
これが私たちが行った水の効果の考古学です
Follow him to investigate
彼を追って調査する
This is our boat in the black ditch
これは黒い溝にある私たちのボートです
a condition of our trawl
私たちのトロール漁の状況
This is where we do our research
ここは私たちが研究を行う場所です
As you can see, this is Baisha Island in Penghu
ご覧のとおり、ここは澎湖県の白沙島です。
This is the main island of Penghu
ここが澎湖本島です
approximate location
おおよその位置
probably at this position
おそらくこの位置で
This is the GPS we passed
これが私たちが渡したGPSです
then do the research
それから研究をしてください
You can find out exactly where these fossils were unearthed here
ここでこれらの化石がどこで発掘されたかを正確に知ることができます
The location of the water is here
水の場所はここです
All of our locations are detailed
すべての場所が詳細に記載されています
Latitude and longitude satellite positioning
緯度と経度の衛星測位
Ding Wei, we also think we should do some science
ディンウェイ、私たちも科学を行うべきだと考えています
not just fishermen
漁師だけではない
We're going to do some scientific research on these
私たちはこれらについて科学的研究を行うつもりです
Then this is the Captain Red just mentioned
それから、これが先ほど言ったキャプテン・レッドです
he is very funny
彼はとても面白いです
He said fishing caught fossils
彼は釣りで化石を捕まえたと言った
One day, a fish will be caught
ある日、魚が釣れる
as look
見ての通り
So it's a fish, right?
それは魚ですよね？
That's what he caught
それが彼が捕まえたものです
It turns out he can't jump this fish
彼はこの魚をジャンプできないことが判明した
right
右
As a look it's a fossil fish
どう見ても魚の化石です
so this is very fun
だからこれはとても楽しいです
he is very happy
彼はとても幸せです
Look at the net tied fish caught fish fossils
捕まえた魚を網で縛った魚の化石を見てください
that this
これは
This is fishing
これは釣りです
he has lots and lots of these
彼はこれをたくさん持っています
larger than class
クラスより大きい
Contains big cattle
大きな牛が入っている
big horse
大きな馬
these deer
これらの鹿
these bones are very
これらの骨はとても
look
見て
This is his casual trip to sea
これは彼の何気ない海旅行です
You can fish so many things up
たくさんのものを釣り上げることができます
These people this is a big
この人たち、これは大きなことだよ
this may be a
これはかもしれない
look at this big buffalo
この大きなバッファローを見てください
This lower goose bone tooth
この下のガチョウの骨の歯は
Just to see these deer bones
この鹿の骨を見るためだけに
this is very, very much
これはとてもとても
So he has a big warehouse at home
それで彼の家には大きな倉庫があります
a big warehouse
一大倉庫
my game is highly recommended
私のゲームは強くお勧めします
I would like to speak to our Vice President Wang
王副社長とお話したいと思います。
Can you buy it?
買ってもらえますか？
baby
赤ちゃん
he put it in the warehouse
彼はそれを倉庫に置いた
I really think it's a waste
本当に無駄だと思う
like that
そのように
This is the Kebao Museum in Taichung
ここは台中の科宝博物館です。
Science and Security Museum
科学と安全保障博物館
This is when they based on these words
このとき彼らはこの言葉に基づいて
recovered
回復した
you see this is a
これはわかりますか
a grimtooth
厳しい歯
This is such a high image
すごく高いイメージです
this thing
このこと
And this is a German buffalo
そしてこちらはドイツ水牛です
It's all based on these bones
すべてはこの骨に基づいています
restored
復元された
It's all very big love is not as tired
それはすべてとても大きな愛です それほど疲れていません
these animals in the past
過去のこれらの動物
When the Taiwan Strait was still land
台湾海峡がまだ陸地だった頃
are in a lot
たくさんいる
very large number of representatives
代表数量非常大
see this as
これを次のように見てください
Just a random tune is so much
ランダムな曲だけでは十分です
So on behalf of the time here is a
それでは、今回の代表として、
Probably grassland or some woods
おそらく草原か森でしょう
So the animals at that time were all roaming around here.
つまり、当時の動物たちはこのあたりを歩き回っていたのです。
so why
なぜ
because at that time this
なぜならその時これは
northern ice age
北方氷河期
It's still too cold in the north
北国はまだまだ寒いですね
So the animals are going south
それで動物たちは南へ行く
So just in Taiwan
それで台湾だけでも
just a little warmer
ほんの少し暖かくなった
They have another source of water here
ここには別の水源がある
Forests and grasslands live here
ここには森と草原が住んでいます
But these animals are not actually
しかし、これらの動物は実際にはそうではありません
its own and at ease
それ自体で安心して
it has an enemy behind it
背後に敵がいる
what enemy
何の敵
there were humans
人間がいた
humans and animals together
人間と動物が一緒に
what are these humans doing
この人間たちは何をしているのですか
of course it has bad intentions
もちろん悪意があります
to kill them
彼らを殺すために
to suffer
苦しむ
Watch carefully
注意深く見てください
we are in the bones
私たちは骨の中にいます
You can find this trace
この痕跡を見つけることができます
What is this trace?
この跡は何でしょうか？
cut by man
人によって切られた
humans want to cut
人間は切りたい
cut off the deer foot
鹿の足を切り落とす
to be its tool
その道具となる
as it is clear from here
ここから明らかなように
This one is on top of this skinny bone
これはこの細い骨の上にあります
There are traces of this cut
この切り傷の跡が残っています
It's clearer here
こちらのほうがわかりやすいですね
this is a deer foot
これは鹿の足です
chopped
みじん切り
use a sharp tool
重い工具を使う
Said to cut off this cut
この切り口を切ると言われました
So this thing represents
つまり、これは
It wasn't just animals
動物だけじゃなかった
there were humans
人間がいた
Humans at that time
あの頃の人間は
Well it's this human
まあ、それはこの人間です
What is the age?
年齢は何歳ですか？
Well past the Museum of Natural Sciences
自然科学博物館を過ぎて
Games that used these painters themselves
これらのペインター自体を使用したゲーム
what about his strategy
彼の戦略はどうですか
It's reversed again
また逆転したよ
It was found that at this age
この年齢で判明したのは、
probably in
おそらく入っているはずです
between 10,000 and 20,000 years ago
1万年から2万年前の間
such an era
そんな時代
About 10,000 to 20,000 years
約1万年から2万年
At most about 30,000 years
長くても3万年程度
But they have been doing it on the mainland for 40,000 years
しかし、彼らは本土で4万年間それを行ってきました
such an era
そんな時代
In this era and just now Dr. Zhang Junxiang
この時代と今 張俊祥博士
The age of Peng Huyuan mentioned is very different.
言及されている彭胡遠の年齢は大きく異なります。
So it was hundreds of thousands of years ago
つまり何十万年も前のことだ
This is 10,000 to 20,000 years
これは1万年から2万年かかる
Then this makes a big difference
そうすれば、これは大きな違いを生みます
So this problem should not be solved yet
したがって、この問題はまだ解決されていないはずです
Are those fossils that old?
それらの化石はそんなに古いものですか？
So what age is it
それで何歳ですか
Is it possible to further determine
さらに特定することは可能ですか
This requires the future
これには未来が必要です
More of these scientific investigations are needed
こうした科学的調査がさらに必要である
So like our underwater valley work
私たちの水中渓谷の仕事のように
Currently working on the sea
現在海で活動中
We also hope to find
私たちも見つけたいと思っています
For some more information on this
これに関する詳細については、
At the same time we also seek to understand
同時に私たちは理解しようと努めます
What was its environment like at that time?
当時の環境はどのようなものでしたか？
Because it's 80 meters underwater 90 meters
水深80メートルだから90メートル
we can't see
私たちには見えません
but we can use these deep sea
でも私たちはこの深海を利用することができます
What about the equipment for taking pictures?
撮影機材はどうなっているの？
Let's observe the sea at that time
その時の海を観察しましょう
what is it like
それはどんな感じですか
what is its terrain like
その地形はどのようなものですか
That's what we have to do
それが私たちがしなければならないことです
an object of study
研究の対象
then this is
それならこれは
This is really human
これが実に人間らしい
This is in Fujian
ここは福建省にある
What about this part of the sea?
この海の部分はどうでしょうか？
found
見つかった
in the Taiwan Strait
台湾海峡で
have found this human
この人間を見つけました
this one
これです
Watch carefully
注意深く見てください
femur
大腿骨
This one is old
これは古いです
this part
この部分
it's a human
それは人間です
So the rep says
そこで担当者はこう言います
was
だった
Not just the discovery of tools made by humans
人間が作った道具の発見だけではない
say cut bones
骨を切ると言う
And there are also human discoveries
そして人類の発見もあります
So the rep says
そこで担当者はこう言います
What about in this sea area?
この海域ではどうなるのでしょうか？
About 10,000 to 20,000 to 30,000 years
約1万年～2万年～3万年
Indeed, there are humans
確かに人間はいる
There are also lots and lots of animals here
ここにもたくさんの動物たちがいます
Then this is an animal paradise
それならここは動物の楽園だ
Humans are also a paradise
人間も楽園だ
Why
なぜ
it has a large number of animals
たくさんの動物がいます
let it go hunting
狩りに行かせてください
it has a lot of rich food
豊かな食べ物がたくさんあります
can live here
ここに住める
And the south is better than the north
そして南は北よりも優れています
It should be warmer
もっと暖かくなるはずです
So it was a time
それで、それは時間でした
Now the Penghu Trench
現在は澎湖海溝です
But it's a very treacherous trench
しかし、それは非常に危険な塹壕です
But 10,000 to 20,000 years ago
しかし1万年から2万年前
This is an animal paradise
ここは動物の楽園です
a paradise for human beings
人間にとっての楽園
This is a
これは
I'll talk about it later
それについては後で話します
This is the world of eight-star power
ここは八つ星の力の世界
If you take a car from Hualien to Taitung
花蓮から台東まで車で行く場合
Hualien to Taitung
花蓮 ～ 台東 航空券
Or go north from Taitung
あるいは台東から北へ
you drive a car
あなたは車を運転します
the east coast is very beautiful
東海岸はとても美しいです
Surrounded by mountains and waters
山と水に囲まれた環境
Green mountains and green waters
緑の山と緑の海
very beautiful
非常に美しい
to the middle point
中間点まで
you will see Eight Star Cave
八星洞が見えてきます
Looking around the Eight Star Cave
八星洞を見て回る
The scenery of Baxing Cave is very beautiful
八星洞の景色はとても美しいです
It is also the middle point between north and south
北と南の中間点でもあります
so many tourists come here
とても多くの観光客がここに来ます
you can take a rest
休んでもいいよ
This is Eight Star Cave
ここは八星洞です
This area is a small hill
このエリアは小さな丘です
Then the road goes down the hill
それから道は丘を下っていきます
If you look closely, on this hill
よく見るとこの丘の上に
many holes
たくさんの穴
at least near the edge of the fog
少なくとも霧の端付近では
There are several big holes
大きな穴がいくつかあります
This hole is very meaningful in terms of geology
この穴は地質学的に非常に意味がある
why
なぜ
Because the formation of this hole is the so-called wave crashing rocks.
この穴の形成はいわゆる波砕石だからです。
Well, of course, if you look at the beach here now
まあ、もちろん、今ここのビーチを見てみると
How did you hit the stone?
どうやって石を打ったのですか？
Actually in ancient times
実は古代には
especially long ago
特に昔から
ten thousand years ago
一万年前
These holes are actually in contact with seawater.
この穴は実際に海水と接しています。
So it means that the seawater probably started after the update ceremony ended
ということは、おそらく更新式が終わってから海水が入り始めたということですね
slowly go up
ゆっくりと上がっていきます
And what about this land?
そしてこの土地はどうなるのでしょうか？
The land on the east coast will also continue to rise
東海岸の土地も上昇し続ける
because of what
何かのせいで
This happens to be on the Eurasian plate
これはたまたまユーラシアプレート上にあります
And around here on the Philippine plate
そしてフィリピンプレートのこのあたり
So what about the movement of this plate?
では、この板の動きはどうなるのでしょうか？
It also contributed to the improvement of the land trade here.
ここの土地貿易の改善にも貢献しました。
That is to say, when the rate of increase and the rate of sea level rise
つまり、上昇率と海面上昇率が上昇したとき
What happens after the two reach a state of equilibrium?
両者が均衡状態に達した後はどうなるでしょうか?
The waves are constantly crashing against this
波は絶えずこれに打ち寄せている
So these caves form a lot of sea rock caves
したがって、これらの洞窟は多くの海岩の洞窟を形成します
so there are many caves
だから洞窟がたくさんある
So this cave is certainly formed by some natural factors
つまり、この洞窟は間違いなく何らかの自然要因によって形成されたものである
But then it became a dwelling place for humans
しかしそこは人間の住処となった
Ancient humans found this good
古代人はこれを良いと感じました
There is such a hole inside the natural
自然界にはこんな穴があるんですね
Can take shelter from the wind
風を避けて避難できる
Such a place where you can avoid the ocean
海を避けられるこんな場所
So it becomes an archaeological site
それで遺跡になる
so humans live here
だから人間はここに住んでいる
So there's a lot left over from his life
だから彼の人生はまだたくさん残っている
So thus it becomes a ruin
こうして廃墟となる
So thus it becomes now a
したがって、今では次のようになります
Because it is a very important site of the country
国のとても重要な場所なので
That's why it's called a national monument
だからこそ国の天然記念物と呼ばれるのです
At the same time, the Management Office of the East Coast National Scenic Office of the Ministry of Communications
同時に逓信省東海岸国家風景局管理室
It is also listed as a National Specific Scenic Area
国の特別名勝にも指定されています
means it has its importance
それは重要性があることを意味します
importance
重要性
There is also a so-called Baxiandong Visitor Center here.
ここにはいわゆる八仙洞ビジターセンターもあります。
If you go to the east coast to play
東海岸に遊びに行くなら
I strongly recommend
強くお勧めします
everyone can stop here
誰もがここで立ち止まることができます
the scenery is very beautiful
景色はとても美しいです
I think the scenery of our Taiwan
私たちの台湾の風景だと思います
Especially the scenery of East Korea
特別東韓的風景
That is, we don't have to travel abroad
つまり海外旅行する必要がないのです
Actually it's good here
実はここがいいんです
If you can stay here for a few days
ここに数日滞在できるなら
you must be a star
あなたはスターに違いない
favorite
お気に入り
this is a very nice place
ここはとても素敵な場所です
This is very but a pity
これはとても残念なことですが
such a nice place
とても素敵な場所
but none of us know
でも私たちの誰も知りません
Nobody knows
誰も知らない
Watch carefully
注意深く見てください
Now since Luke opened
ルークがオープンしてから
look here
ここを見て
There is a car here every day
ここには毎日車が来ます
Dozens of cars are parked on the side of the road
道路脇に数十台の車が停まっている
what is he doing
彼は何をしているの
has two purposes
2つの目的があります
There is a visitor center here
ここにビジターセンターがあります
To the restroom
トイレへ
So many people have to go to the toilet
トイレに行かなければならない人がたくさんいる
so that toilet is kept clean
トイレがきれいに保たれるように
also keep cleaning
掃除も続ける
because there are too many people
人が多すぎるので
the second
二番目
There is a temple just by the road
道路のすぐそばにお寺があります
Lingyan Temple
霊岩寺
go in and have a look
中に入って見てください
Burning Township
バーニング・タウンシップ
This is the Eight Immortals Cave
ここは八仙洞です
then left
それから去った
or there is a restaurant here
またはここにレストランがあります
then have a lunch
それから昼食をとる
then left
それから去った
So tens of thousands of people
だから何万人も
this tourist comes here
この観光客はここに来ます
But I believe almost no one knows
でも、ほとんど誰も知らないと思います
This turned out to be a very important archaeological site
ここは非常に重要な遺跡であることが判明しました
And it's a national monument
そして国の天然記念物です
so it's a pity
だから残念だ
So where is the important line from this site?
では、このサイトの重要な行はどこにあるのでしょうか?
This was in the 57th year of the Republic of China
これは中華民国57年のことでした。
Professor Song Wenxun of National Taiwan University
国立台湾大学 宋文勲教授
So he found the culture of the old times over there
そこで彼はそこに古い時代の文化を見つけました
He named it Changbing Culture
彼はそれを長平文化と名付けた
This is the senior who was guided by our Shi Yu at that time
あの時私たちのShi Yuが指導してくれた先輩です
Changbing Culture named by Mr. Li Ji
李吉氏が命名した長平文化
So Professor Song did excavations here
そこでソン教授はここで発掘を行いま​​した
Excavations dug up these so-called old times
発掘調査により、いわゆる古い時代が掘り出されました
That was the first time in Taiwan to discover the culture of the old era
台湾で初めて古い時代の文化を発見しました
Well, at that time, he also made some age determinations.
まあ、そのとき、彼は年齢の決定もしました。
Then he discovered that in this era
そして彼はこの時代にあることに気づきました
Looking at it from here, it is about 5,000 years old
ここから見ると樹齢約5000年
About 5300 years, 5400 years
約5,300、5,400
So this is probably about 5,000 years ago
ということは、これはおそらく5000年ほど前のものだと思われます
Only one age is above the tallest cave
最も高い洞窟の上にあるのは 1 つの年齢だけです
a year unearthed
発掘された一年
It is called greater than 15,000 years
15,000年以上と言われています
but it doesn't know how many years
でも何年になるか分からない
The result is that
結果は、
Possibly greater than 15,000 years old
おそらく15,000年以上前のもの
more than 15000
15000以上
but how many years
でも何年
Because of the limited technology at that time
当時の技術には限界があったため、
So it has no way to understand
だからそれは理解する方法がない
so this becomes one big one puzzle
これは 1 つの大きなパズルになります
How old is this White Star Cave?
この白星洞は何年前のものですか?
According to reason, it is the era of the era
理由によれば、それは時代の時代です
Should be at least 10,000 years old
少なくとも10,000年前のものである必要があります
Why is it only 5,000 years old
なぜたった5000年しか経っていないのか
And here it is 15000
そしてこれが15000です
how much is it
いくらですか
How many thousands of years?
何千年？
so no one knows
だから誰も知らない
But after the discovery of Nagahama's English culture
しかし、長浜の英語文化を発見してからは、
But it has become one of our Taiwan's history
しかしそれは私たちの台湾の歴史の一つになりました
very important one
とても大切なもの
Take a look at our elementary school textbooks
小学校の教科書を見てみましょう
middle school textbooks
中学校の教科書
Its first one talks about the culture of the period
最初の部分では当時の文化について語られています。
Must talk about Nagahama
長浜について語らなければなりません
Nagahama English culture
長浜市の英語文化
But many students ask
しかし、多くの学生はこう尋ねます
After all, you are not talking about the culture of the period
結局のところ、あなたはその時代の文化について話しているのではありません
would it have been 10,000 years ago
1万年前だろうか
Why is this place more than 5,000 years old?
なぜこの場所が 5,000 年以上の歴史があるのでしょうか?
So in the end this 15,000 years is just greater than
つまり、この 15,000 年は結局のところ、
How long have you been looking for it?
どれくらい探していましたか？
so no one knows
だから誰も知らない
So it becomes a question mark
だから疑問符になるんだよ
a question
質問
what about this thing
これはどうですか
so until a few years ago
だから数年前までは
The Ministry of Culture is looking for us
文化省が私たちを探しています
Hope to do some further research
さらなる研究をしたいと考えています
investigate to understand
理解するために調査する
Because after the 57th year of the Republic of China, Professor Song
なぜなら、民国57年以降、宋教授は
no one does research anymore
もう誰も研究しない
No one has done research for decades
何十年も研究した人はいない
But the question is still hanging there
しかし、疑問はまだ残っています
still need to solve
まだ解決する必要があります
At that time, Professor Song
その時、ソン先生は、
He also made some inductions on Changmin culture
彼はまた、チャンミンの文化についてもいくつか紹介しました
he said first
彼が最初に言った
He said at that time
その時彼は言いました
There was no farming phenomenon at that time
当時は農業という現象はありませんでした
At that time, no one was found at this time
この時点では誰も見つからなかった
he can recrop
彼は再収穫できる
no agricultural phenomenon
農業現象がない
the second
二番目
these people
この人達
he won't grind period
彼は生理を我慢しない
to be naughty
いたずらする
Those things are in line with
それらのことは一致しています
A basic definition of the so-called old culture
いわゆる古い文化の基本的な定義
Another third is
さらに3分の1は、
Times are all tricks to beat waves
時間は波に勝つためのすべてのトリックです
no grinding period
研削期間なし
It's time to make
作る時間です
then in addition
それからさらに
It belongs to the entire eastern part of Asia
アジアの東部全体に属します
as well as the southern tradition called kanfa
カンファと呼ばれる南部の伝統と同様に
Therefore, cutting gas represents a period
したがって、ガスの切断は周期を表します。
The kind of felling gas used to chop things
物を切断するために使用される伐採ガスの種類
an industrial tradition
産業の伝統
So it made an induction on the time
それで、それは時間通りに誘導を行いました
This induction is basically correct
この帰納法は基本的には正しい
But they all lack some more detailed understanding
しかし、それらはすべて、より詳細な理解が欠けています
This was also guessed by Professor Song at the time.
これは当時の宋教授も推測していた。
Where did Taiwan's product culture come from?
台湾の製品文化はどこから来たのでしょうか？
So he also made some guesses
それで彼もいくつかの推測をしました
So it may still come from most of the South Seas
したがって、それは依然として南洋のほとんどから来ている可能性があります
In this region of the South China Sea
南シナ海のこの地域では
So the discovery of this product culture
この製品文化の発見
It is very important to the history of Taiwan
台湾の歴史にとって非常に重要です
It is also Taiwan that can push Taiwan's history forward
台湾の歴史を前進させることができるのも台湾です
earlier time
もっと早い時間
But many issues still need to be understood
しかし、まだ多くの問題を理解する必要がある
to solve
解決する
Especially to understand the human beings of the old times
特に昔の人間を理解する
then we need more of this information
それなら、もっとこの情報が必要です
So therefore I personally probably just
したがって、私は個人的にはおそらくただ
It also introduces about from 1997 of the Republic of China
中華民国の1997年以降についても紹介
We also accept this document will
この書類も受け付けます
Now the Ministry of Culture and Taichung publicity entrust
現在は文化部と台中の広報委託
We also implement a further step to do this
これを行うためのさらなるステップも実装します
The Eight Immortals Cave who joined the army
入隊した八仙洞
This research that has been investigating
調べ続けてきたこの研究は、
we hope to understand
私たちは理解したいと思っています
Of course, we also set a lot of agenda
もちろん、たくさんの議題も設定しました
to understand further
さらに理解するために
to learn about
について学ぶ
Then this is that we will do it more systematically than before
それから、これは今までよりも計画的にやっていくということでございます。
It is our whole team and the process of work
それは私たちのチーム全体であり、仕事のプロセスです
Work has a SOP process
作業にはSOPプロセスがある
We do scientific research
私たちは科学研究を行っています
do research
研究を行う
then this is
それならこれは
Then we this after a few years
そして数年後にこれが出来上がります
The most important first is that we're going to discover new holes
まず最も重要なことは、新しい穴を発見することです
why now
なぜ今なのか
This was the era of Professor Song Wenxun
宋文勲先生の時代です。
the cave he made
彼が作った洞窟
his own cave
彼自身の洞窟
Regrettably
残念ながら
when the work is done
仕事が終わったら
what has become of this cave
この洞窟はどうなったのか
into a ready-made temple
既成の神殿に
A lot of
たくさんの
After you dug the hole there was a hole there
穴を掘ったらそこに穴があった
It's just right to go in and set up a few lanes
入って数レーンを設けるのがちょうどいい
put a few buddhas
仏様を何体か入れて
After the diary has an appointment, it becomes an altar
日記は約束があれば祭壇になる
a temple language
寺院の言葉
So almost all the holes above are occupied by these temple words
つまり、上の穴のほとんどすべてがこれらの寺院の言葉で占められています
Then it will do temple language
それから寺院語を行います
while doing some construction inside
内部で工事をしているときに
to dig out the soil
土を掘り出す
Then put some altars
それから祭壇をいくつか置きます
So the chair was destroyed again.
それで椅子はまた壊れました。
Below is broken even if possible
以下はできても壊れています
Therefore, there is probably no way to do further research on these hole sequences.
したがって、これらの穴の配列についてこれ以上研究する方法はおそらくありません。
So it is necessary to find a new hole sequence
したがって、新しい穴シーケンスを見つける必要があります
our part
私たちの部分
So we have to do a survey
そこで調査をしなければなりません
so you pay attention
だから注意してください
This is our new survey in recent years
これは近年の新しい調査です
Therefore, quite a few new hole sequences have been discovered.
したがって、かなりの数の新しい穴配列が発見されています。
this is quite difficult work
これはかなり難しい作業です
Because these holes are not there waiting for you to discover
なぜなら、これらの穴はあなたが発見するのを待っているわけではないからです
In fact, you all know that landslides
実は土砂崩れは皆さんご存知ですよね
right
右
landslides
土石流没上
Especially typhoons on the east coast
特に東海岸の台風
There are many landslides
土砂崩れが多い
Just cover all the caves
すべての洞窟をカバーするだけです
are full
いっぱいです
so can't see at all
だから全く見えない
so we're going to find the cave
それで洞窟を探しに行きます
Especially thick straight batches
特に太いストレートバッチ
plant covered
覆われた植物
So it's very difficult to keep working
だから仕事を続けるのはとても難しい
especially in many places
特に多くの場所で
because it is a wall
壁だから
So it's pretty dangerous to work
だから作業するのはかなり危険だよ
like here
ここのような
These are very steep walls
これらは非常に険しい壁です
look for a group of caves
洞窟群を探す
But our team members
しかし、私たちのチームメンバーは、
It's all very risky
それはすべて非常に危険です
adventure flood
冒険の洪水
So go in and look slowly
だから中に入ってゆっくり見てください
through some expert methods
いくつかの専門的な方法を通じて
through some means
何らかの手段を通じて
Then put the caves one by one
次に、洞窟を 1 つずつ配置します。
can find out
知ることができる
So you can't see part of the cave at all
洞窟の一部がまったく見えない
go find the cave again
もう一度洞窟を探しに行きます
So now it becomes so many caves
それで今はたくさんの洞窟になっています
So this means
つまり、これは意味します
At that time the area
当時の地域は
when it was formed in the sea stone cave
海石の洞窟で形成されたとき
Actually formed a lot of caves
実際にはたくさんの洞窟が形成されていました
at different times
さまざまな時に
because as the crust rises
地殻が上がると
so it slowly
だからゆっくりと
highly eroded
高度に侵食された
like the earliest ones are relatively high range
初期のものは比較的高音域のようです
Then when the Disk rises
そしてディスクが上昇すると
There is also a range of lower erosion
より低い浸食範囲もあります
Then Disk goes up again
その後、ディスクは再び上昇します
and erosion further down
そしてさらに下に浸食
so the higher the cave
だから洞窟が高いほど
it should be earlier
もっと早いはずだ
then the lower cave
それから下の洞窟
it will be later
それは後になります
then this is
それならこれは
You are big enough to see the tallest cave above
あなたは上にある最も高い洞窟が見えるほど大きいです
probably here
おそらくここ
Currently found to be about 200 meters high
現在の高さは約200メートルであることが確認されています
about 30 meters down there
そこから30メートルくらい下に
30 meters
30メートル
represent different times
さまざまな時代を表す
The caves formed by these
これらによって形成された洞窟は、
this is
これは
after we found out
私たちが知った後
Kangjia Skills of Science and Ancient Science
Kangjia の科学と古代科学のスキル
Excavation after investigation
調査に次ぐ発掘
why
なぜ
you from the bunker
バンカーから来たあなた
Information available to you
入手可能な情報
is limited after all
結局のところ限られています
you have to dig under it
あなたはその下を掘る必要があります
Because the artifacts of ancient humans
古代人類の遺物だから
slowly with time
ゆっくりと時間とともに
buried under the ground
地面の下に埋もれている
So you have to go through a scientific
したがって、科学的な検査を通過する必要があります
a systematic approach
体系的なアプローチ
dig your stuff out
自分のものを掘り出す
and then be able to do some research
そして、いくつかの研究ができるようになります
Then these are the ones we choose
それから、これらが私たちが選ぶものです
some caves of different heights
さまざまな高さのいくつかの洞窟
to carry out
実行する
to dig
掘る
Digs represent different times
ディグはさまざまな時間を表します
The connotations in also represent different eras
の含意もさまざまな時代を表しています
So we work like this
だから私たちはこのように働きます
This is our different choice of blood
これは私たちの異なる血液の選択です
different heights for digging
掘るためのさまざまな高さ
from the actual meter
実際のメーターから
The last track is close to the height of 200 meters
最後のトラックは高さ200メートル近くです
Excavation actions are carried out in different blood movements
掘削動作はさまざまな血液の動きで実行されます
This is what we're digging
これが私たちが掘っているものです
Very hard
とても厳しい
inside this move
この動きの中で
Under the ground after punching in
パンチイン後の地面の下
Often can reach seven or eight meters
多くの場合、7〜8メートルに達することがあります
very deep
非常深
especially in summer
特に夏に
It's airtight inside
中は気密です
So our staff worked very, very hard
だから私たちのスタッフはとても一生懸命働きました
and very dangerous
そしてとても危険です
why
なぜ
On top of the hole there will continue to come down
穴の上には引き続き実装されます
Because the above will continue to implement
上記は引き続き実装されるため、
so what do our workmates bring
それで、私たちの同僚は何を持ってきますか
with helmet
ヘルメット付き
Come on, why is the hat being implemented and smashed like this
おいおい、なんで帽子が実装されてこんなに潰れてるんだろう
this is a very
これはとても
but very important
しかし、とても重要です
So in this
それで、これで
You can find many of these things in it
その中でこれらのことをたくさん見つけることができます
As an ordinary person but do not know
一般人には分からないので
say it's all stone
全部石だと言う
We often have many people ask us tourists
観光客の方からよく質問されることがありますが、
what is this
これは何ですか
He said no
彼はノーと言った
We see a lot of seaside
海辺がたくさん見えます
Nice by the sea
海沿いで素敵です
These stones are from the sea
これらの石は海から来たものです
Humans at that time picked these stones from the sea
当時の人類はこの石を海から拾い上げました
They choose stones purposefully
彼らは意図的に石を選びます
Then the stone itself is processed to make its stone tools
その後、石そのものを加工して石器を作ります。
So you can see this is
これを見るとわかりますが、
What I just said is that I will get angry
今言ったことは怒るってことだよ
it uses these pebbles from the sea
海で採れた小石を使用しています
Then come here after the wave
波が終わったらここに来てください
knock down the flakes
フレークをたたき落とす
Then there are some seals here
それからここにいくつかのシールがあります
These seals can have the function of cutting
これらのシールには切断機能があります。
or cut hair function
またはカットヘア機能
So probably in the past these humans
だからおそらく過去にはこれらの人間は
It's actually not like copper and iron now
実際、今は銅と鉄のようなものではありません
It's exactly when it needs to work
まさに仕事が必要なときです
Go to the beach and cut these pebbles and come back
ビーチに行って小石を切って戻ってくる
and then to process
そして処理するために
then do it
じゃやれ
We also did a lot of experiments
私たちもたくさんの実験をしました
How did this human do it?
この人間はどうやってそれをしたのでしょうか？
We went to get the stone ourselves
自分たちで石を取りに行きました
Knock, knock, wow, I can't knock on that one, my hands are numb
ノック、ノック、うわー、ノックできない、手がしびれている
He couldn't knock a piece down. It was very difficult.
彼は駒を一つも倒すことができず、とても難しかったです。
very difficult with this stone
この石では非常に難しい
very hard
とても厳しい
Basalt stone is very hard
玄武岩石はとても硬いです
It's very, very difficult for you to knock it down
それを打ち倒すのはとてもとても難しい
My hands are so skinny I can't knock them off
私の手はとても細いので、落とすことはできません
Later we experimented with various methods
その後、さまざまな方法を試しました
Later found a fastest way
後で最速の方法を見つけました
These people just need to drop on the ground
これらの人々はただ地面に落とすだけです
he actually cracked
彼はほとんど崩壊した
and he cracked beautifully
そして彼は見事に割れた
Then do local processing on top
次にローカル処理を上で実行します
Then these methods will be formed
その後、これらのメソッドが形成されます
That's why we call it the Wrestling Method
それが私たちがそれをレスリングメソッドと呼ぶ理由です
may have produced such a
そのようなものを生み出したかもしれない
This is what we found through our experiments
これが私たちの実験でわかったことです
such a result
そのような結果
Learn about the technology of human beings making stone tools at that time
当時の人類の石器製作技術を学ぶ
Also we are inside this hole
私たちもこの穴の中にいる
have been excavated very carefully.
非常に丁寧に発掘されています。
We did it to see that there is a firepit here
ここにファイヤーピットがあることを確認するためにやったのです
The location of each of these stone tools
それぞれの石器の位置
This means that human beings in this cave at that time
これは、当時この洞窟に人類がいたということを意味します。
just forming
ちょうど形成されている
It went in when it just came out of the water
水から上がったばかりのときに入ってしまいました
so we'll find a lot of pebbles inside
だから中にはたくさんの小石が見つかるでしょう
In addition, they use these pebbles to make stone tools
また、この小石を使って石器を作ることもあります。
then inside it maybe when hunting
それからおそらく狩りのときにその中にいます
There is barbecue grilled food
バーベキューグリル料理あり
So there's a lot of these fire sugar in the hole
穴の中にはファイアーシュガーがたくさんある
So fire sugar make fire sugar A fire sugar B
だから火の砂糖は火の砂糖Aを作ります火の砂糖Bを作ります
That is to say, the fire sugar is the place where the fire is burned.
つまり、火砂糖は火が燃える場所です。
So here we can find traces of the fire at that time
ここで当時の火災の痕跡を見つけることができます
So on behalf of the human beings at that time
だから当時の人類を代表して
This so-called time like Mao drinking blood
毛沢東が血を飲むようなこのいわゆる時間
They make stone tools in the cave
洞窟で石器を作っている
cook food in it
その中で食べ物を調理する
The event of its whole life is its cave
その生涯の出来事はその洞窟です
then in this hole
それからこの穴の中で
Also found some of this
こんなものも見つけました
what does this look like
これは何に見えますか
just naughty
ただいたずらなだけ
The one in front of it is completely irrelevant
手前のものはまったく関係ありません
This is the human race of the New Era, about 3,000 years old.
これは新時代の約3000年前の人類です
It means that human beings tens of thousands of years ago
ということは、人類は数万年前に
thousands of years of human beings
何千年にもわたる人類
it will use animals
動物を使うことになる
come as a residence
住居として来る
So humans in the past served as nest dwellers
つまり、過去の人間は巣の住人として働いていた
so tree dwelling
だから木の住まい
and cave dwellers
そして洞窟住居
is to use different terrain
異なる地形を使用することです
living place
居住地
we did too
私たちもそうでした
The chronological analysis just mentioned
先ほど述べた時系列分析
Well now we do quite a bit of this
さて、今私たちはこれをかなりやっています
In the past in the era of Professor Song Wenxun
昔、宋文勲先生の時代
Due to technical limitations
技術的な制限のため
How many years did he do it
彼は何年それをやりましたか
and the age of doubt
そして疑いの時代
we pass these
私たちはこれらを渡します
Our new technological approach
私たちの新しい技術的アプローチ
we can do a lot
私たちはたくさんのことができます
Now there are seventies and eighties
今は70代と80代がいる
so its overall channel is very high
全体的なチャネルが非常に高いため、
from the current age
今の年齢から
The earliest we can reach 30,000 years
最速で3万年に到達できる
Can reach 30,000 years of data
30,000 年分のデータに到達可能
Watch carefully
注意深く見てください
this is all we have
私たちが持っているのはこれだけです
Pay attention to our data
私たちのデータに注目してください
line up
並ぶ
The earliest age here is 30,000 years old
ここでの最も古い年齢は3万歳です
and then sorted all the way down
そして最後まで並べ替えました
Generate a GAP here
ここでギャップを生成します
Down from about 5,000 years ago
約5000年前から
down again
再びダウン
like until now
今までのように
Well, what is very beautiful about this age is the data of this age
さて、この時代で非常に美しいのは、この時代のデータです
here is very meaningful
ここはとても意味のあることです
I won't talk about it here because it's another academic question.
それはまた学術的な問題なのでここでは話しません。
In fact, this age is probably the earliest at the current location
実はこの年代が現在地では一番早いのではないかと思われます。
At the current height, the age is about 30,000 years
現在の高さで年齢は約3万年
Now tell me what I've said so far
さあ、これまで私が言ったことを教えてください
Humans of our Changmin culture, the age of the eight stars
私たちのチャンミン文化の人間、8 つの星の時代
about 30,000 years ago
約3万年前
So the humans here are probably the earliest
つまりここにいる人類がおそらく最古の人類だろう
up to 30,000 years
30,000年まで
These are the results obtained so far
これまでに得られた結果です
In addition, we are also concerned about the accumulation of strata in this cave
また、この洞窟内の地層の堆積も懸念されます。
Some made this Poxi in great detail
このPoxiを非常に詳細に作成した人もいます
As a matter of fact this is a cave and these accumulations of this formation
実際のところ、これは洞窟であり、この地層の蓄積物です。
this is very interesting
これはとても興味深いです
From the heap we don't just learn that it's a natural process
ヒープから、それが自然なプロセスであることを学ぶだけではありません
Because the cave itself its original
洞窟自体がオリジナルなので
here are big pebbles
ここに大きな小石があります
This represents when the cave was formed
これは洞窟が形成された時期を表しています
Pebbles from the sea will rush into the hole
海からの小石が穴に突入します
Then slowly began to deposit on the top
それからゆっくりと上部に堆積し始めました
This deposit may have flowed in from outside the cave.
この堆積物は洞窟の外から流入した可能性があります。
these grades
これらのグレード
then to the top
それから頂上へ
Come back and find that the score is oblique
戻ってきてスコアが斜めになっていることに気づく
top is flat
上部は平らです
Why? Because it's late in the month
なぜか? 月末だから
maybe a natural disaster
もしかしたら自然災害かもしれない
earthquake
地震
So the hole is blocked
それで穴は塞がれた
After blocking
ブロック後
This grade outside
外ではこのグレード
Only through some very small forces
いくつかの非常に小さな力を通してのみ
Or the force of the water rushing into the hole
あるいは穴に流れ込む水の勢い
We found that around 3000 years
約3000年前に発見された
probably all the holes
おそらくすべての穴
basically blocked
基本的にブロックされています
this thing is very
これはとても
let's analyze the soil
土壌を分析しましょう
analyze the rock
岩を分析する
we can learn
私たちは学ぶことができます
A change in the natural environment reflected at that time
当時の自然環境の変化を反映
and natural disasters
そして自然災害
Especially in Baxian East area
特に八県東エリア
Until now
今まで
there are many disasters
災害がたくさんあります
rockfall anytime
いつでも落石
collapse at any time
いつでも崩壊する
so this disaster
それでこの災害は
Since ancient times, only
古来より、ただ、
So this also reflects
これも反映されていますので、
Humans at that time
あの頃の人間は
Especially we found in the stratum
特に地層で発見したのは、
people come and go
人々が行き来する
come and go
行ったり来たりする
came again after leaving
帰ったらまた来てね
That this and the natural environment
これも自然環境も
and natural disasters are basically closely related
と自然災害は基本的に密接な関係があります
Then of course we also want this
それからもちろんこれも欲しいです
These data also help us to understand
これらのデータは、私たちが理解するのにも役立ちます
Where did these humans come from?
この人間たちはどこから来たのでしょうか？
In the past, Professor Song Wenxun speculated that it might have come from South China
過去に宋文勲教授は、それが中国南部から来たのではないかと推測した
In this regard, we basically do not deny him.
この点に関して、私たちは基本的に彼を否定しません。
But we also considered his possible ties to the south
しかし、私たちは彼が南部と関係がある可能性も考慮しました
relationship with the Philippines
フィリピンとの関係
There are many problems
問題はたくさんあります
We still need to go further to do some discussions
さらに議論を進める必要がある
The other is our past geology
もう一つは私たちの過去の地質です
I have always wanted to know the address on the east coast of Taiwan
台湾東海岸の住所をずっと知りたいと思っていました
The rate of crustal rise is the fastest in the world
地殻上昇の速度は世界最速
very fast rise every year
毎年非常に速いペースで上昇
We can also take advantage of the heights of the different caves in the Eight Immortals Cave
八仙洞のさまざまな洞窟の高さを利用することもできます。
have the exact age
正確な年齢がある
Let's estimate the address on the east coast
東海岸の住所を推定しましょう
What is the rate at which the ground rises?
地面が隆起する速度はどれくらいですか?
So it's because each of our caves is to me
それは、私たちのそれぞれの洞窟が私にとってのものだからです
and then its higher level
そしてそのより高いレベル
It can be inferred from this aspect
この側面から推測できるのは、
rate of increase per year
年間増加率
Looks like every year from now
これから毎年のようです
Probably the time when the East China Sea rose was about 7
おそらく東シナ海が隆起したのは7時頃だったと思います。
Up to 10 mm is quite a fast speed.
10mmまではかなり速いです。
So some of us speculate that this is after the customs year
したがって、私たちの中には、これは関税の年の後ではないかと推測する人もいます
Taitung's Green Island Blue Rain will slowly approach the East China Sea
台東の緑島の青い雨がゆっくりと東シナ海に近づく
because he's been sliding
彼は滑り続けているから
I'm improving
改善しています
So this is the 88 first move
これが88の初手です
In fact, since about 30,000 years ago
実は約3万年前から
Humans live there
そこに人間が住んでいる
then he will come and go
そうすれば彼は行ったり来たりするだろう
It lasted until about 15,000 years ago.
おそらく15,000年まで続いたと思われます。
Finally another group of people came in again
ついにまた別のグループが入ってきた
Then after 3000
それから3000以降
there is another group of people
別のグループがいます
So these studies can help us understand
したがって、これらの研究は私たちが理解するのに役立ちます
what about the cave area
洞窟エリアはどうですか
The life of these human beings
この人間たちの人生は、
And some changes in his culture
そして彼の文化にもいくつかの変化があった
This is our guess
これは私たちの推測です
Some states of human life at that time
当時の人間の生活のいくつかの状態
Then let's talk about another topic
それでは、別の話題について話しましょう
This is the farmer who came across the sea
海を渡って来た農夫です
Well, this was just mentioned earlier
まあ、これは先ほども言いましたが、
So while we're talking about Conanco
それでコナンコの話をしている間に
As the one I saw, this dog
私が見たのと同じように、この犬は
what is this
これは何ですか
It's a dog, isn't it?
犬ですね。
It's so cute as a dog.
犬みたいでとても可愛いですね。
sleep here
ここで寝てください
we are normal now
私たちは今は普通です
if dead
死んでいれば
Of course our times are different now
もちろん今は時代が違います
now your pet
今あなたのペット
if passed away
亡くなった場合
if after death
もし死後に
not only to bury it properly
きちんと埋めるだけではなく
cremate it
それを火葬します
to put in the tower
塔に入れる
to confess
告白する
someone wants to put it in the house
誰かが家に置きたいと思っています
treat it like a baby
赤ちゃんのように扱う
in ancient times
古代では
I usually imagine
普通に想像してるよ
This dog is dead
この犬は死んだ
throw it outside
外に放り出す
eat yourself and leave it alone
自分で食べて放っておいてください
But in our Tainan Science Park
しかし、私たちの台南サイエンスパークでは
5000 years of farmers
農民の5000年
look at his dog treat like this
彼の犬がこのように扱っているのを見てください
he did a very good job of burying him
彼はとても上手に埋葬した
So after the dog died
それで、犬が死んだ後、
so look what he's doing really well
だから彼が本当にうまくやっているのを見てください
bury it
埋めろ
not a dog
犬ではありません
There are many dogs like this
こういう犬はたくさんいるよ
So this means
つまり、これは意味します
One between man and dog
人間と犬の間にあるもの
very close relationship
非常に親密な関係
This is what we have found in Taiwan so far
これは私たちがこれまで台湾で見つけたものです
The earliest dog bred by humans
人間によって飼育された最初の犬
We call it Taiwan's No. 1 Dog
私たちはそれを台湾No.1の犬と呼んでいます
Ha ha
ははは
This Taiwanese native dog is the first dog in Taiwan
この台湾原産の犬は台湾初の犬です
We also found it here
ここでも見つけました
this rice just said
このお米は今言った
This is the first rice in Taiwan
これが台湾初のお米です
The earliest rice found in Taiwan
台湾で発見された最古の米
5000 years
5000年
Of course, this era is still later than other regions.
もちろん、この時代は他の地域に比べればまだ遅い。
Like the current era of rice in mainland China
現在の中国本土の米の時代のように
up to 20,000 years
20,000年まで
By 19,000 years to 20,000 years
19,000年から20,000年までに
We have now found the earliest rice in Taiwan
台湾最古の米を発見
or until 5000
または5000まで
Then this millet
それからこのキビ
This is the first discovery in Taiwan
台湾では初の発見です
We know that the aborigines of Taiwan have so far
私たちは、台湾の原住民がこれまでに
Millet is a very important crop
アワは非常に重要な作物です
Therefore, we must use millet in the new year
したがって、新年にはキビを使用する必要があります
Then use millet to make wine
次にキビを使ってワインを作る
but where did this millet come from
しかしこのキビはどこから来たのですか
when did millet start
キビはいつから始まりましたか
never knew
知らなかった
Now through our archaeological discoveries
考古学的発見を通じて
Also found a lot of millet
キビもたくさん見つかりました
This millet does not come by accident
このキビは偶然に生まれたものではありません
Or snatched from the sea
あるいは海から奪ったもの
or how
あるいはどうやって
it's a lot
それは多い
And the millet is all burnt
そしてご飯も全部焦げてしまいました
The representative said that the amount was very large
代表者はその金額が非常に大きいと述べた
it may burn it when lether
放っておくと燃えてしまう可能性があります
Just as Lesser's positive attitude towards Fang
レッサーのファングに対する積極的な態度と同じように
So the representative said that when
そこで代表者はこう言いました。
this amount is quite large
この金額はかなり大きいです
Not that it takes money to buy very precious
とても貴重なものを買うのにお金がかかるわけではない
So the rep said
そこで担当者はこう言いました
At that time, a multi-functional representative of human beings
当時、人類の多機能な代表者
So on behalf of the agriculture at that time
当時の農業を代表して
it grows rice on the one hand
一方では米を育てる
grow millet on the one hand
一方でキビを育てる
Of course there is a problem
もちろん問題はある
Because millet grows in a more temperate region
キビはより温帯な地域で育つため、
The subtropical zone in our southern Taiwan
私たちの台湾南部の亜熱帯地帯
upper tropics
上部熱帯地方
How can millet be produced
キビはどのようにして生産されるのか
This part is of course also a question
この部分も当然疑問です
But we also know that climate change
しかし、私たちは気候変動も知っています。
Today's climate may not have been the same in the past
今日の気候は過去と同じではなかったかもしれない
And the environment in which they were planted was not necessarily the same.
そして、それらが植えられた環境は必ずしも同じではありませんでした。
so it is still possible to grow millet
したがって、まだキビを栽培することは可能です
Now in the tribes of the aborigines in eastern Taiwan
現在は台湾東部の原住民族に
There are many kinds of rice
お米の種類もたくさんあります
There are two ruins in the area of ​​Taiwan Academy of Sciences
台湾科学院の敷地内には2つの遺跡があります
one is what we call
1つは私たちが呼んでいるものです
This is a Nanguanli
これは南関里です
Nanguan Lidong Ruins
南関立東遺跡
These are the two oldest ruins
これらは最古の 2 つの遺跡です
Just five thousand years
たった五千年
It unearthed our first dog in Taiwan
台湾で初めて犬が発掘されました
Also produced Taiwan's first grain of rice
台湾初の米も生産された
Taiwan's first millet
台湾初のキビ
This is when we are working
これは私たちが仕事をしているときです
as look have very hard
見ての通りとても大変です
This has a large area of ​​excavation
ここは発掘範囲が広い
Then these peasants of this culture
それから、この文化のこれらの農民たちは、
it all comes from
それはすべてから来ています
are from
からのものです
are from mainland
本土出身です
Probably the coast of Guangdong
おそらく広東省の海岸です
They are all the generation of the Pearl River Delta
彼らは皆珠江デルタの世代です
because of the culture there
そこの文化のせいで
These cultures are very similar
これらの文化は非常に似ています
The representative said that these human beings
代表者は、これらの人間は、
Probably from the Guangdong Delta
おそらく広東デルタ出身
even further south
さらに南へ
One North to Hainan Island
海南島まで北へ一本
this coastal generation
この沿岸世代
probably all these people
おそらくこの人たち
probably his original hometown
おそらく彼の本来の故郷
or these people cross the sea
あるいはこの人たちは海を渡る
came to these Taiwan
この台湾に来ました
this is
これは
As a look at his technologies at that time
当時の彼の技術を見てみると
has made great progress
大きな進歩を遂げました
very nice these naughty
とても素敵です、これらのいたずらな
Very beautiful these stone tools
とても美しい石器です
These stone tools are very delicate as a model
これらの石器は模型としては非常に繊細です
And back
帰ってきた
These backs are used for
これらのバックは次の目的で使用されます。
as a knife for harvesting
収穫用のナイフとして
these rice crops
これらの米作物
You see this has a very nice back knife
これはとても素晴らしいバックナイフを持っているのがわかります
As these tools for reaping antiquities
骨董品を採取するための道具として
And the counterpoint to what I just said
そして、私が今言ったことの反対語
Made book cover
ブックカバーを作りました
and these
そしてこれら
It is also sold
こちらも販売しております
There are also some sold tools
販売されている工具もあります
that is its settlement
それがその決着だ
a very complete settlement
非常に完全な和解
contains channels
チャンネルが含まれています
There is a river
川があります
have a house
家がある
with stick
スティック付き
The whole is in the settlement
全体は和解にあります
After representing the people at that time
当時の人々を代表して
There is a very stable settlement
非常に安定した決済が行われています
it's not an oily
油っぽいものではありません
Mobility
可動性
After it came to Taiwan from the mainland
大陸から台湾に伝わってから
it chooses
それが選ぶ
I just talked about the beach near the sea
海の近くのビーチについて話したところです
live here
ここに住んでいます
so it does farming
それで農業をするのです
to engage in fishing hunting
釣り狩猟に従事する
then there is a very good one
それからとても良いものがあります
a complete society
完全な社会
Social Structure
社会構成
the whole society
社会全体
it for this environment
それはこの環境のためです
can have very good adaptation
非常に良い適応ができる
And its position
そしてその位置
Right on top of the sand dunes by the sea
海沿いの砂丘のすぐ上
so the location it lives in
だからそれが住んでいる場所
and the habitation of its past continents
そして過去の大陸の居住地
basically something like
基本的に次のようなもの
So representing an immigrant
つまり移民を代表して
go from one place to another
ある場所から別の場所に行く
He still hopes to maintain
彼はまだ維持したいと考えています
his original habits
彼の元々の習慣
can also live in
に住むこともできます
similar to his living environment
彼の生活環境と似ている
in this environment
この環境で
So in the past on the southeast coast of the mainland
それで昔、本土の南東海岸で
it lives by the sea
それは海のそばに住んでいます
live in the dunes
砂丘に住んでいます
Taiwan still chooses sand dunes to live in
台湾は今でも砂丘を選んで住む
This is it also has a cemetery
ここには墓地もあります
from its grave staff
その墓の杖から
Has a very complete tomb staff
非常に充実した墓スタッフがいる
have fixed customs
固定された習慣がある
The tomb staff of the people here are completely facing south.
ここの人々の墓標は完全に南を向いています。
not facing north
北を向いていない
So it must be a special custom
だから特別な習慣なんだろうね
then its source
それからそのソース
We speculate that it may have come from the coast of Guangdong
私たちはそれが広東省の海岸から来たのではないかと推測しています。
from the south of Fujian
福建省南部から
Get this Hainan strip in the north of Hainan Island
海南島の北部にあるこの海南ストリップを手に入れましょう
this is its old home
ここが彼らの古い家です
such a source
そのようなソース
In fact, it’s not just that we are in Taiwan
実は、私たちは台湾にいるだけではありません
to the whole world
全世界へ
also has its significance
意味もあります
why
なぜ
Because now we are talking about the origin of the so-called Austronesian people
なぜなら今私たちはいわゆるオーストロネシア人の起源について話しているからです
because everyone needs to know
誰もが知る必要があるから
The Austronesian peoples are from the southeast coast of the mainland
オーストロネシア人は本土の南東海岸の出身です
and then migrated southward
そして南へ移動した
then to the pacific
それから太平洋へ
current residence
現在の居住地
these austronesian peoples of the pacific
太平洋のオーストロネシア人たち
think a lot of it comes from
その多くはから来ていると思います
from the southeast coast of this continent
この大陸の南東海岸から
and Taiwan
そして台湾
Then our discovery in Tainan Branch
そして台南店で見つけたのは
for such a theory
そのような理論に対して
has a supporting role
サポート的な役割を持っています
Of course there are different views
もちろん違う意見もありますが
But now the mainstream
しかし今では主流となっている
is such a mainstream
それはとても主流です
So our findings are even stronger
したがって、私たちの調査結果はさらに強力です
such a view
そんな景色
Of course we also did it
もちろん私たちもやりましたよ
According to our own material
弊社独自の資料によると
Also made a lot of corrections
修正もたくさんしました
this is a
これは
so we Taiwan
だから私たち台湾
Its discovery is not just of significance to Taiwan
その発見は台湾にとって重要なだけではありません
and has worldwide significance
そして世界的に重要な意味を持っています
tell another story
別の話をする
stonemason on a desert island
無人島の石工
this is very interesting
これはとても興味深いです
it is this
これです
This so-called desert island
いわゆるこの無人島
Refers to Qingmei Island in Penghu
澎湖県の清美島を指します。
what time is it now
今何時ですか
Ome Island on this deserted island
無人島の青梅島
This island is actually for going to Ome
実はこの島は青梅に行くためのものなんです
very beautiful
非常に美しい
But it's a desert island
でもそこは無人島だ
no one
誰も
And the traffic is very inconvenient
そして交通がとても不便です
We are going to Penghu
私たちは澎湖へ行きます
all of us are
私たち全員が
The deepest impression must be that everywhere is black
最も深い印象は、どこもかしこも真っ黒だということでしょう。
black stones everywhere
どこにでもある黒い石
Why
なぜ
Because there are a lot of basalt rocks here
ここには玄武岩がたくさんあるので、
The basalt is of course harming it
玄武岩はもちろん害を及ぼします
because it's
それはだから
due to address
住所のせいで
Because after the past volcanic eruptions in Penghu
澎湖県では過去に火山噴火があったため、
Much of its magma is transported to flow out
マグマの多くは運ばれて流出する
many so-called basalts
多くのいわゆる玄武岩
So you can see basalt rocks everywhere in Penghu
澎湖ではどこでも玄武岩を見ることができます。
Well, this basalt is generally called black stone.
さて、この玄武岩は一般的に黒い石と呼ばれています。
its texture is very hard
質感はとても硬いです
It can be divided into different categories
さまざまなカテゴリに分類できます
A so-called fine basalt
いわゆる上質玄武岩
The other is called subtractive basalt
もう一つは減算玄武岩と呼ばれます
Then the texture of this reduced basalt is relatively fine
この還元玄武岩の組織は比較的細かいです
The texture of fine basalt is more airy
上質な玄武岩の質感はより軽やかです
There are often bubbles that are softer
柔らかい泡がよく出ます
So these are two different
つまり、これら 2 つは異なるものです
This form of basalt
この玄武岩の形
Well, on Qimei's side
さて、キメイの側では
mostly reduced basalt
大部分が還元された玄武岩
so its texture is very hard
そのため質感は非常に硬いです
and meticulous
そして几帳面な
This is in Qimei area
ここは七美地区にあります
Then when the volcano erupted
その後、火山が噴火したとき、
After the magma flows out
マグマが流れ出た後
Its form will produce many
その姿は多くのものを生み出します
this so-called contact
このいわゆる連絡先
Du Zhuang's end of this phenomenon
杜荘によるこの現象の終焉
like this
このような
as watch by the sea
海辺で見守るように
You can see that it looks like this when you hit the top here
ここを上に当てるとこんな感じになるのがわかります
This is how it looks when you look up close
近くで見るとこんな感じです
very beautiful
非常に美しい
This is a kind of duzhuang ending
これは一種の都荘エンドです
This is because after the gushing out along the river
川沿いに湧き出たあとだから
its special shape
その特殊な形状
a special form of
特別な形の
this condensation
この結露
This warm diarrhea it becomes a
この温かい下痢は
very important ingredient
非常に重要な成分
Then this ancient man was very smart
それでこの古代人はとても賢かったのです
it found the stone
それは石を見つけた
Its texture is very fine
質感がとても細かいです
very hard
とても厳しい
So he thinks this ingredient is
そこで彼は、この成分は次のように考えています。
can be used as an important tool for it
そのための重要なツールとして使用できます
an ingredient
成分
see this as
これを次のように見てください
then until now
それから今まで
These Penghu residents
澎湖県民の皆さん
Still use a lot of these ingredients
今でもこれらの食材をたくさん使用しています
including construction
建設も含めて
Holy Child Contains Faith Inside Temple
聖子には神殿の中に信仰が込められている
holy children art
聖なる子供たちの芸術
It's all a lot of just using this ingredient
この材料を使うだけでたっぷりです
Xuanwu Garden as a look at the buildings that contain it
玄武園を含む建物を眺める
The twin-heart stone household that contains Sheng Erqinmei
盛二琴梅を含む双心石家
They also use these big stones from Xuanwu Garden
玄武園の大きな石も使用しています。
piled up
積み上げ
these are works of art
これらは芸術作品です
Therefore, for the residents of Penghu, this Xuanwu Garden
つまり、この玄武園は澎湖住民のためのものなのです
is a very important ingredient
非常に重要な成分です
It is also an important food industry
重要な食品産業でもあります
So we are in Ome Island
ということで青梅島に来ました
I did the survey in 1983
私は1983年に調査を行いました
We will do it when we get to Ome Island
青梅島に着いたらやります
just like us
ちょうど私たちのような
Go everywhere to find these ancient relics
古代の遺物を見つけるためにどこにでも行きます
found a large number of these stone tools
これらの石器が大量に発見されました
There are many stone tools
石器がたくさんある
very tree very big
とても大きな木
I was skeptical
私は懐疑的でした
This stone so many stone tools
この石には石器がたくさんあります
Not many people live on the island
島にはあまり人が住んでいません
why does it have
なぜそれがあるのですか
so many stone tools here
ここには石器がたくさんあります
Almost densely packed with stone tools
石器がほぼ密集している
if the population is very small
人口が非常に少ない場合
It doesn't need so many stone tools
それほど多くの石器は必要ありません
to make tools
道具を作る
So I guessed
それで私は推測しました
this may have other meaning
これには別の意味があるかもしれない
it may be a factory
工場かもしれない
or as a production and marketing
または制作およびマーケティングとして
a factory of stone tools
石器の工場
So this one finally hits the year 2000
いよいよ2000年を迎えます
At that time, I was in the same university as the next one.
当時、隣の大学と同じだったんです。
A Berry Rollade
ベリー・ロレード
and what we can do
そして私たちが持っているもの
a professor's researcher
教授の研究者
Also retired Ye Xuewen Professor Ye
葉学文教授も退職
Let's go to Qinmei to have a look
秦美へ行って見ましょう
take a look
見てください
Later, when we arrived at Qinmei, we discovered that
その後、秦美に到着してわかったことは、
Sure enough, I found out that my statement was confirmed.
案の定、私の発言が確認されたことがわかりました。
I found several so-called large
いわゆる大型をいくつか見つけました
The so-called period factory
いわゆる時代工場
What is period factory
時代工場とは
It was the ancient humans
古代の人類
Every day in the manufacturing period
製造期間中の毎日
A lot of waste will be generated after the manufacturing period
製造期間後には大量の廃棄物が発生します
So pile it on the ground
だから地面に積み上げて
pile up like a mountain
山のように積み重なる
So it becomes one we call
それで、それは私たちが呼ぶものになります
Besides, I pack a lot of tools of the production period inside
他にも内部には製作当時の工具を多数詰め込んでいます
So this is a period factory
つまり、ここは時代工場です
This is our Qin Meidao
ここは私たちの秦美島です
Qinmei Island is a very beautiful island
秦美島はとても美しい島です
So look at this island is the roundabout
だから見てくださいこの島はロータリーです
then on this coast
それからこの海岸で
There are many strong knots
強い結び目がたくさんあります
This kind of Xie Lianzhu who promotes the five words exists
五つの言葉を推進するこのような謝連珠が存在する
Here become ancient humans
ここが古代人類になります
important field of its choice to real estate
不動産という重要な選択分野
So ancient humans were very intelligent
つまり古代人は非常に知性が高かったのです
where do these people come from
この人たちはどこから来たのですか
from Taiwan
台湾から
So they came to Peng Hua
それで彼らは澎華にやって来ました
They chose a place to live
彼らは住む場所を選びました
This place is called Nangang Ruins here
ここは南港遺跡と呼ばれる場所です
This island seems to be
この島はどうやら
It's a place where you can dig the ground and prepare for the wind.
地面を掘って風に備える場所です。
Because the northeast monsoon in Penghu is very strong
澎湖県の東北モンスーンは非常に強いため、
So they chose here to make a settlement
そこで彼らは和解するためにここを選んだ
gather here
ここに集まってください
Then the wind can block the wind
そうすれば風が風を遮ってくれる
And then a little village sits here
そして小さな村がここにあります
What are these people doing?
この人たちは何をしているのですか？
what is his only job
彼の唯一の仕事は何ですか
Just after going out during the day
日中外出した直後
Just to this coastal area
まさにこの海岸地帯まで
What about these three places?
この３か所はどうでしょうか？
Come and find ingredients
材料を探しに来てください
tableware
打食器
So we envy them
だから私たちは彼らを羨ましいと思う
Here I live as if it expires American drama
ここで私は期限切れのように生きています アメリカのドラマ
This is Twin Star Ishido
ツインスター石堂です
very beautiful
非常に美しい
the sea is very beautiful
海非常美 非常美
These people sit there every day and hit stones
この人たちは毎日そこに座って石を叩いている
I think they play folk songs and hit rocks for a year
彼らは1年間フォークソングを演奏したり、ロックを叩いたりしていると思います
really sit every day
本当に毎日座ってます
But it's also boring to think about
でも考えるのも退屈だ
but it's very
でもそれはとても
Then there are several large
それから大きなものがいくつかあります
This stone tool factory along the coast
海岸沿いにある石器工場
This is what made stone tools at that time
これが当時の石器を作ったものです
And what about this part?
そして、この部分はどうでしょうか？
watch this
これを見て
this is what we did
これが私たちがやったことです
This help has also been excavated
こんなヘルプも発掘されました
Watch carefully
注意深く見てください
At that time, I helped so I saw naughty
あの時、手伝ってくれたのでエッチな姿を見てしまった
This secret is crazy
この秘密はクレイジーです
The representative lived here for a rather long
代表者はここにかなり長く住んでいた
Then there's a long time here
それからここでは長い時間がかかります
Then there are personal ones buried here
ここには個人的なものが埋葬されています
Those who saw people die here are buried here
ここで人々が死ぬのを見た人はここに埋葬されています
so it's not a temporary
だからそれは一時的なものではない
it lives here
それはここに住んでいます
So people are buried here when they die
だから人は死ぬとここに埋葬される
it won't ship back its old furniture
古い家具は返送されない
buried here
ここに埋葬されています
The representative here is a jade
ここの代表は翡翠です
this is a jade
これは翡翠です
The representative said that the jade from Taiwan
代表者によると、台湾産の翡翠は、
they can also bring
彼らはまた持ってくることができます
Jade
ジェイド
This is the era we did
これは私たちがやった時代です
Dated to 3800 at the latest
遅くとも3800年まで遡る
as early as 4200
早ければ4200
this era
この時代
represents 3800 years
3800年を表す
people here at this time
この時間にここにいる人々
Living on Ome Island
青梅島在住
what they do is make stone tools
彼らがやっていることは石器を作ることです
I'm going out to see this one
これを見に出かけます
Most people can't understand these stones
ほとんどの人はこれらの石を理解できません
I can't even read it the first time
初めてでも読めない
Later, when I went again, I found
その後、もう一度行ったときに見つけたのが、
There are many mysteries in it
その中には多くの謎がある
inside these stones
この石の中に
I go out to see
見に出かけます
It's full of scraps from making stone tools.
石器を作る際の端材が詰まっています。
This scrap it doesn't break down naturally
このスクラップは自然には割れません
it is cracked
ひび割れています
So from many traces
それで、多くの痕跡から
I can tell
私が言うことができる
most obviously this
最も明白なのはこれ
This is called Northwest Bay
ここはノースウェストベイと呼ばれています
This one is an original manufacture period
こちらはオリジナルの製造時期のものです
after a long time
長い時間が経ってから
Then it's left on the ground again
そしてまた地面に放置される
Various scraps of the period when these were made
製作当時の様々なスクラップ
so much waste
とても無駄が多い
piled up thick
厚く積もった
There is almost no natural stone in it
天然石はほとんど入っていません
They are all scraps from the manufacturing period.
全て製造時に出る廃棄物です。
There are many, many tools from these manufacturing periods in the middle
中間にはこれらの製造時代の非常に多くのツールがあります
The so-called tools are masonry stones
いわゆる道具は石積みです
is to hit stone with stone
石と石をぶつけることです
so there are some tools
だからいくつかのツールがあります
As look here there are many
ここを見てみるとたくさんあります
this wonderful one
この素晴らしいもの
This is probably all over the world
これはおそらく世界中にある
To find such a complete period manufacturing site
このような完全な時代の製造現場を見つけるには
almost very hard
ほとんどとても難しい
we have some in the pacific
太平洋にもいくつかあります
Mainland China has some
中国本土にはいくつかの
But an immobile like this
しかし、このような不動車
4,000-year-old
4,000年前
Such a site is probably basically
このようなサイトはおそらく基本的に
one is hard to find again
再び見つけるのは難しい
Because there is Qimei, no one goes
奇美があるから誰も行かない
also did not destroy
破壊もされていない
So here every year through things
だから毎年ここで物事を通して
Spring, summer, autumn and winter go round and round
春、夏、秋、冬が巡る
It's been like this for four thousand years
4000年もの間ずっとそうなのですが、
it's always been like this
いつもこうだった
so when i look at it
それでそれを見ると
I feel my heart will be excited
心がワクワクしそうな気がします
I feel that between the ancients
古代人との間でそう感じます
It's the feeling of meeting
会う感覚です
Can feel the ancients here
ここで古代を感じることができます
the way you work
あなたの働き方
so in my head
だから私の頭の中で
can emerge
出現することができます
So this was what shocked me at the time.
それで、これが当時私に衝撃を与えたものでした。
this discovery
この発見
We have also done a lot of analysis during these periods
この期間中、私たちは多くの分析も行いました
found inside
中で見つかった
so many stones inside
中には石がたくさん
In fact, it can be divided into several categories
実はいくつかのカテゴリーに分類できます
One category is rock that hits fast
カテゴリーの 1 つは、速攻でヒットするロックです
just a stone
ただの石
they from this
彼らはこれから
after moving above
上に移動した後
to make a knock down
ノックダウンする
become a crashing stone
砕ける石になる
Then generate some stone boxes
そしていくつかの石の箱を生成します
So the stone box is a mother stone
つまり、石箱は母石です
The above can be further processed
上記はさらに加工できます
A call to make stone tools
石器作りの呼びかけ
Then come the flakes
それからフレークが来ます
Stone flakes are a basic material for further processing
石のフレークはさらなる加工のための基礎材料です
Then it becomes a blank and a material
それからブランクとマテリアルになります
Then make a blank in the manufacturing period with the material
その後、製造時にその素材でブランクを作ります。
And then there are some stone remnants
そして、石の残骸がいくつかあります
So remnants are tools
つまり残骸は道具だ
this stone grass it produces a blemish
この石草は傷を生み出す
Or it breaks and it's lost
あるいは壊れて紛失してしまう
Because there are too many stone residues
石の残骸が多すぎるので
it doesn't need to stay
留まる必要はない
it breaks and throws it away
壊れて捨ててしまう
So often found a very beautiful period
とても美しい時代がよく見つかります
But it will be discarded if there is a catastrophe in the middle
ただし途中で大惨事があれば廃棄される
Because it is a relatively complete
比較的完成度が高いので、
It is good
いいですね
There are also pebbles
小石もあります
What are stone tools?
石器とは何ですか？
It's a tool to beat the times
時代に勝つためのツールです
then this is
それならこれは
As a look at this is a so-called stone
これは一見するといわゆる石です
a most primitive stone
最も原始的な石
then slowly beat down
それからゆっくりと倒します
turn into small pebbles
小さな小石に変わる
then come again
それからまた来てください
this is a flake
これはフレークです
a large square
大きな広場
or rectangular flakes
または長方形のフレーク
and then after the challenge
そしてチャレンジ後は
These stone flakes
この石の破片は
Then it slowly took shape
それから徐々に形になっていきました
This is a
これは
as a round blank imagining a period
期間をイメージした丸い空白として
For example, a rectangle
たとえば、長方形
above is where you can shake hands
上は握手できる場所です
Below is a windblade
下は風刃です
It's the wind blade of a utensil
道具の風刃です
this location
この場所
then it becomes
そうすると、こうなります
then slowly take the next step
それからゆっくりと次の一歩を踏み出してください
becomes a
になる
After correction
修正後
this fixed
これは修正されました
just a small waste
ほんの小さな無駄
smaller waste
より小さな廃棄物
and then finally becomes a
そして最終的には
a period of formation
形成期
everybody look
みんな見て
letter
手紙
those people are smart
あの人たちは賢いです
he ends here he ends
彼はここで終わる、彼は終わる
he didn't do it
彼はそれをしませんでした
why not
なぜだめですか
he doesn't need to do it anymore
彼はもうそれをする必要がない
It is enough for him to ship this back to Taiwan
彼にとってはこれを台湾に送り返せば十分だ
And then processed after arriving in Taiwan
台湾到着後に加工
So he also had this
それで彼はこれも持っていました
On the one hand, there is the concept of industry collapse
一方で、産業崩壊という概念もあります。
on the one hand also what
一方ではまた何ですか
The concept of processing export zones
加工輸出区域の概念
want to be interesting
面白くなりたい
when he does
彼がそうするとき
Why
なぜ
He doesn't want to move the whole rock back to Taiwan
彼は岩全体を台湾に戻すことを望んでいない
We have to cross the black ditch in the middle
真ん中の黒い溝を渡らなければなりません
very difficult, right?
とても難しいですよね？
even in the qing dynasty
清朝でも
The Han people want to cross the black ditch
漢民族は黒い溝を越えようとしている
Ten people have seven berths
10人で7寝台
Ten ships have seven berths silent
10 隻の船が 7 つの寝台で静かです
that they
彼らは
don't have to move the boulder back
岩を元に戻す必要はありません
After he has increased to this level?
ここまでレベルが上がったら？
reprocessing in Taiwan
台湾での再処理
So this is a
これは
The system of people at that time, the wisdom of ancient people
当時の人々の仕組み、先人の知恵
Then this is the tool of his manufacturing period
では、これが彼の製作時代の道具です
This has been hammered in vain
これは無駄に叩かれました
it has been tied
それは結ばれています
Do you see it
あなた見えますか
There was a seal and it was flat
シールが付いているものは平らになっていました
There are so many things like this
こういうのってたくさんあるんですね
Look at these tools
これらのツールを見てください
This manufactures tools at ten kilometres.
これは 10 キロ離れた場所で工具を製造します。
Then we based on these things
次に、これらのことに基づいて、
we can restore it back then
当時に戻すことができます
Steps in each manufacturing period
各製造時期の工程
can restore it
復元できる
one recovered
1人は回復した
Then this is the person we imagined at the time
では、これが当時私たちが想像していた人物です
how to make period
生理の作り方
This step draws it
このステップで描画されます
see this as
これを次のように見てください
This is the whole Ome Island
これが青梅島全体です
above this
この上に
This is where the drama of it falls
ここにドラマが起こるのです
Humans sleep here at night
人間は夜ここで眠る
sleep
寝る
he goes out during the day
彼は日中外出します
Go to this location where there is this injection of Xuanwu Garden
Xuanwu Gardenのこの注入があるこの場所に行きます
then what
じゃあ何
just step on the stone and hit
石を踏んで叩くだけ
Watching the sea and singing folk songs every day
毎日海を眺めながら民謡を歌っています
then this
それからこれ
then stop after
その後停止します
Just after forming a batch
バッチを形成した直後
then here
それからここで
It just so happens that this is a bay
たまたまここが湾だった
bay
湾
Then it's out to sea
それから海に出ます
Then it can be shipped elsewhere
その後、別の場所に発送することもできます
Where does this luck go?
この幸運はどこへ行くのでしょうか？
This is one of Japan's era scholars Kokubu
日本時代学者の国分です
he also studies
彼も勉強しています
He found that in southwestern Taiwan
彼は台湾南西部でそれを発見した
From south of Taichung
台中南部から
Probably to the generation of Pingtung
おそらく屏東の世代まで
Many wills are unearthed inside the period
期間内から多数の遺書が発掘される
Xuan Wuyan
スアン・ウーヤン
That's where Xuan Wuyan came from
それがスアン・ウーヤンの出身地です
He presumed it was from Penghu
彼は澎湖産だと推定した
So he was the first to bring up
それで彼が最初に持ち出したのは
So Xuanwuyan in southern Taiwan
台湾南部の蘇玄武岩
is a scholar from Penghu
澎湖出身の学者です
Now our findings can be further confirmed by
私たちの調査結果は、次の方法でさらに確認できます。
Watch carefully
注意深く見てください
This is the period of Xuanwuyan in southern Taiwan
これは台湾南部の玄武岩の時代です。
is very beautiful
とても美しい
right
右
The model is very delicate
モデルはとても繊細です
This is not available in Penghu
澎湖では利用できません
right
右
Penghu means
澎湖語の意味
After he punched out the fur of the thing
彼はその毛皮を打ち抜いた後、
Shipped to Taiwan
台湾に発送
and then process
そして処理します
then spread out
それから広げます
So the rep said
そこで担当者はこう言いました
The earliest processing export zone
最古の加工輸出地帯
this
これ
I didn't know if I slept
寝たかどうか分からなかった
do not know
わかりません
then this is
それならこれは
Watch carefully
注意深く見てください
The period of this stone in Taiwan
台湾におけるこの石の時代
are very delicate
とても繊細です
So our hypothesis
そこで私たちの仮説は
Penghu Century Factory
澎湖世紀工場
It is not just the meaning of manufacturing technology
製造技術だけではない
it was at the time
それは当時でした
ancient human trade
古代の人間の貿易
The circulation of the goods
商品の流通
In fact, it also has a very important meaning in it.
実はそこにはとても重要な意味も含まれています。
Then this part of its circulation
次に、その循環のこの部分
On the one hand to Taiwan
一方では台湾へ
it is mostly southern taiwan
ほとんどが台湾南部です
It is almost not found in northern Taiwan
台湾北部ではほとんど見られません
from Taichung
台中から
South of Zuoshuixi
左水渓の南
It has probably been this generation until Pingtung
屏東まではおそらくこの世代だったでしょう
Another scholar's
別の学者の
Research by foreign scholars
外国人学者による研究
On Dongshan Island in Fujian
福建省の東山島にて
some periods unearthed inside the chair
椅子の中で発掘されたいくつかの時代
After some isotopic analysis
いくつかの同位体分析の後
Analysis of trace elements
微量元素の分析
It was also found that these things all came from Penghu Island
これらはすべて澎湖島から来たものであることも判明した
So this thing becomes very interesting
それで、これは非常に興味深いものになります
Therefore, the period of Qimei Island in Penghu
したがって、澎湖七美島の時代は、
It is not only to Taiwan
台湾に限らず
It also went to Fujian
福建省にも行きました
So this represents five thousand years in ancient times
つまり、これは古代の5000年を表します
four to five thousand years ago
4～5千年前
Here is a very important
ここで非常に重要なことが
one place with one meaning
一つの場所に一つの意味がある
many people ask me
多くの人が私に尋ねます
He said what ship he was on
彼はその時どの船に乗っていたかを言いました
It is not so easy to cross the black ditch
黒い溝を越えるのはそう簡単ではない
I said I'm sorry I don't know
ごめんなさい、分かりませんって言いました
we didn't find
私たちは見つかりませんでした
We can only speculate that probably
おそらく推測することしかできませんが、
Because motor boats were impossible at the time
当時はモーターボートは不可能だったので
may be troublesome
面倒かもしれない
to take advantage of the good weather
良い天気を利用するために
to cross the trench
溝を越えるために
but sea trench
でも海溝
Although it is about sea trenches
海溝の話ですが
It's actually very difficult
実はとても難しいんです
Our School Archeology Team
私たちの学校考古学チーム
Experience crossing the sea trench several times
海溝を何度も渡った経験
it is very difficult
それはとても難しいです
very thrilling
とてもスリリングな
So four or five thousand years ago in ancient times
つまり、4、5千年前の古代には
how do humans carry so many stones
人間はどうやってそんなにたくさんの石を運べるのか
How to cross the sea trench
海溝を渡る方法
From Penghu to Taiwan
澎湖から台湾へ
From Penghu to Fujian
澎湖から福建へ
This is a big puzzle
これは大きなパズルです
we all need
私たち全員が必要です
On the one hand we are wary
一方で私たちは警戒しています
the wisdom of the ancients
古代人の知恵
On the one hand we are also very
一方で、私たちもとても
how to solve this puzzle
このパズルを解く方法
ancient humans
古代人類
Here is a model we built
これが私たちが構築したモデルです
these are the ingredients
これらが材料です
between the whole area
エリア全体の間
in trade
貿易中
A model generated
生成されたモデル
this is ours
これは私たちのものです
relationship of our time
私たちの時代の関係
i want the fastest
最速が欲しいです
tell me again
もう一度お願いします
then another
それからもう一つ
Sea Wonders
海の驚異
we know taiwan
私たちは台湾を知っています
You are studying and don't know
勉強しているのに知らないのでしょう
Taiwan is in the whole of East Asia
台湾は東アジア全体にある
One of the centers of a very important anticipation
非常に重要な期待の中心の 1 つ
As long as China is a big country
中国が大きな国である限り
There are several important prospective centers on the mainland
本土には将来有望な重要なセンターがいくつかある
Hongshan Culture in the Northeast
東北の紅山文化
Two Groups of Cultures in the South
南部の 2 つの文化グループ
in Hangzhou, Zhejiang
浙江省杭州で
Then the Gansu area in the west
それから西の甘粛地域
are the centers of several important expectations
いくつかの重要な期待の中心である
Taiwan is one of them
台湾もその一つです
is also an important center of anticipation
期待の重要な中心でもあります
why
なぜ
Because there is a bathroom in Taiwan
台湾にはトイレがあるので
Fengtian Field in East Hualien
花蓮東の奉天場
it is a domain
それはドメインです
thus creating Taiwan
こうして台湾が誕生する
for thousands of years
何千年もの間
is a very important anticipation center
非常に重要な期待中枢です
About five thousand years ago
約5000年前
Humans have already started using anticipation
人類はすでに期待を使い始めている
current expectations
現在の期待
In all the ruins in Taiwan
台湾のあらゆる遺跡で
Both found the expected
どちらも期待どおりの結果を見つけました
inclusive from north to south
北から南まで包括的
From Main Island to Outer Islands
本島から離島へ
almost all expected
ほぼ全て予想通り
Just like Green Island and Orchid Island, both have been found and expected
緑島と蘭島と同様に、両方とも発見され、期待されています。
I remember two years ago
2年前のことを思い出します
I went to Green Island to see a ruin
緑島に遺跡を見に行ってきました
the surface of the ruins
遺跡の表面
you can't see anything
何も見えない
I see a friend go
友達が行くのを見ました
a foreign scholar
外国の学者
His purpose is to find expectations
彼の目的は期待を見つけることです
Looking for a long time is very disappointed
長い間探していたのは非常に残念です
We don't see
見えない
As a result, when I want to turn back later
その結果、後で引き返したいときに
I kicked
私は蹴った
just kick out a bath gas
お風呂のガスを追い出すだけです
so he is envious
だから彼は羨ましいです
he has medicine
彼は薬を持っています
i said no
私はノーと言った
This is the heritage of our country's culture
これは我が国の文化遺産です
you can't take it
あなたはそれを受け入れることができません
this
これ
We know that the current bath gas in Taiwan
私たちは台湾の Yuqi を知っています。
very widely distributed
非常に広く分布している
this
これ
I think the relationship of this time
今回の関係だと思います
Most of them are in Taitung
そのほとんどは台東にあります
transplant
移植
it unearthed bath gas
バスガスを掘り出しました
Much
非常多
Now there are more than five or six thousand pieces
今では5、6千個以上あります
unearthed from the same transplant
同一個移植所出土的
the bath gas itself
バスガスそのもの
can be divided into several categories
いくつかのカテゴリに分類できます
One is the so-called decorator class
1 つはいわゆるデコレータ クラスです。
Light Drama
光劇類
Weapons
武器類
You can look at these pictures
これらの写真を見ることができます
very beautiful
非常に美しい
The technology of our Taiwan bath gas
弊社の台湾バスガスの技術
Actually it's not bad at all
実際は全然悪くないよ
not bad at all
悪くない、全く
So I speak Haiyu Qipan
だから私はハイユ・キパンを話します
In Taiwan's Haiyu Barren State
台湾の海嶼不毛地帯で
inside this corner
この角の内側に
there are still
まだあります
there is such a beautiful
こんなに美しいものがあります
craft of healing
癒しの工芸品
everybody look
みんな見て
The bath gas is very beautiful
お風呂のガスがとても綺麗です
very beautiful
非常に美しい
The bath quality is also very beautiful
お風呂の質もとても綺麗です
everybody look
みんな見て
these are earrings earrings
これはイヤリングです
look
見て
Different kinds
異なる種類
These II, you see
これら II は、わかりますか
Compared with the jade aura of the mainland, this is actually true
本土の翡翠の精神と比較すると、これは実際に真実です
It really doesn't matter in terms of craftsmanship, craftsmanship, or shape
職人技、職人技、形状などはまったく関係ありません。
Actually not bad
実は悪くない
Look at this is very beautiful jade gas
見てください、これはとても美しい翡翠ガスです
This and this very famous
これとこれは非常に有名です
The so-called life type has a birthday
いわゆるライフタイプには誕生日があります
such two people
そんな二人
This Taiwan has now discovered that there are two or three worlds
この台湾は今、世界が 2 つまたは 3 つあることを発見しました
Such a kind of jade appears
こんな翡翠も登場
very beautiful
非常に美しい
This is Taitung Stone Statue Red Museum
こちらは台東石像紅博物館です
You take this as its authority
あなたはこれを権威だと思っています
You guys look very beautiful too
あなたたちもとても美しいですね
Then this is another site outside the North and South
それから、これは北と南の外の別の場所です
Also found the same kind of jade gas
同種のヒスイガスも発見
Look at these gems
これらの宝石を見てください
So Taiwan's jade gas is very exquisite
台湾の翡翠ガスは非常に優れています
it has such an important
それはとても重要なことを持っています
Ten thousand generations of ancient humans in Taiwan
台湾の1万世代の古代人類
In fact, there is such a very important tradition of jade
実際、翡翠には非常に重要な伝統があります。
Then this is this is a jade tube
それからこれは翡翠の管です
That's a puzzle too
それもパズルだよ
It can be up to 30 cm in length
長さは最大30cmにもなります
Such a long, very narrow, small round tube
このような長くて、非常に細く、小さな丸い管
available from this
ここから入手可能
can penetrate to the other side
向こう側まで貫通できる
so you use water
だから水を使うんですね
This side can be used as a water pipe
こちら側は水道管としても使えます
can flow to the other side
向こう側に流れることができる
so this is a puzzle
これはパズルです
how did you do it
どうやってやったの？
ten generations before
十世代前
Well this is on top of the world
まあ、ここは世界の頂点です
It's hard to have such expectations
そんな期待を持つのは難しい
such a long tube
こんなに長いチューブ
this is very delicate
これはとてもデリケートです
And the middle will not be broken
そして真ん中は壊れない
And penetrate
そして浸透します
This craft is very rare
この工芸品は非常に珍しいです
This section has been a few months ago
このセクションは数か月前に行われたものです
Implemented as national security by the Ministry of Culture
文化省が国家安全保障として実施
This is the expectation of the national security level
これは国家安全保障レベルの期待値です
this is very beautiful these
これはとても美しいですね
This pre-value is very good pre-value
このプレ値は非常に優れたプレ値です
you want to do this
あなたはこれをしたいのですか
I want everyone to take a look
みんなにも見てほしい
Then this expected mineral source
そして、この期待されるミネラル源は
The only source of minerals in Taiwan is here
台湾唯一の鉱物資源はここにある
In the so-called Toyota domain
いわゆるトヨタの領域で
Well, recently our colleagues are here
さて、最近私たちの同僚がここにいます
also do research
研究もする
Several new ruins were discovered
新たな遺跡がいくつか発見された
near here
ここの近く
Anyway, here is a mining area near here
とにかく、ここの近くに鉱山があります
So a lot of the anticipation is coming from this area
この分野には多くの期待が寄せられています
what is expected of its production
その生産に何が期待されているか
not just to north and south
北と南だけではなく
North-South is a consumer
北と南は消費者です
Then he actually changed his steps to Taiwan from high to low
そして実際に台湾への歩みを高から低へと変えた。
From the main island to the outer islands, the whole island is
本島から離島まで島全体が
So on behalf of a trade network about expectations at that time
そこで貿易ネットワークを代表して当時の予想について
It's a big trade network
それは大きな貿易ネットワークです
Thousands of years ago, these beautiful expectations of human beings
数千年前、人類が抱いた美しい期待
circulates throughout this
この全体を循環します
But apart from Taiwan
でも台湾以外では
In fact, more importantly
実際、もっと重要なことは、
This is this, this, this, this, this, this, roe
これは、これは、これは、これは、これは、いくらです
This wind is called Hirabayashi roe
この風を平林の風と呼ぶ
i want to take a look
見てみたいです
This one has a lot of manufacturing expectations on top of the roe
これは卵の上に多くの製造上の期待を持っています
leftover scrap
残ったスクラップ
You see he was making an expectation
彼が期待していたのがわかりますね
he wants to be round
彼は丸くなりたい
He can't be cut with wire now
今ではワイヤーで切ることはできない
He cut it piece by piece like this
こんな感じで一枚一枚カットしてくれました
look over there
向こうを見て
After the corners are cut slowly
角をゆっくりカットしてから
Then grind it into a round
その後、丸く研磨します
It's a waste of work
仕事の無駄だよ
But he made so many expectations
しかし、彼は非常に多くの期待をしました
It means that apart from the tools at that time
ということは、当時の道具とは別に、
Maybe there was a lot of manpower at that time, and he looked like this
おそらく当時は人手が多かったのでこんな感じだったのではないでしょうか？
So so create these expectations
したがって、これらの期待を生み出します
Well, this is how to make
さて作り方はこんな感じです
Our scholars have done a lot of research in this area
私たちの学者はこの分野で多くの研究を行ってきました
how to make these expectations
こうした期待をどのようにして実現するか
how to use
使い方
Then the other is the expectation
それからもう一つは期待です
Not only in Taiwan
台湾に限らず
one of my students
私の生徒の一人
he did research
彼は研究をしました
He expected Taiwan
彼は台湾を期待していた
do some component analysis
成分分析をする
him and the philippines
彼とフィリピン
and Thailand
そしてタイ
and analysis done elsewhere
他の場所で行われた分析
Found in Vietnam and Thailand
ベトナムとタイで発見
Thailand's Indochina Peninsula
タイのインドシナ半島
Southside has some expectations
サウスサイドには期待がある
Almost from Taiwan
ほぼ台湾から
Feng Tian from Taiwan
奉天 台湾
Then the scientist
すると科学者は
our geoscience institute
私たちの地球科学研究所
Dr. Zong Fan
ゾン・ファン博士
He also helped out with some testing.
彼はまた、いくつかのテストを手伝ってくれました。
found that it looks from the ingredients
成分から分かることが分かりました
From the characteristics it seems
特徴からするとそう思われます
In fact, in many places in Southeast Asia
実際、東南アジアの多くの場所で
Expected to be from Taiwan
台湾出身と思われる
Therefore, on behalf of Taiwan, these expectations at that time
したがって、台湾を代表して、当時のこれらの期待
It is not only circulated in the islands of Taiwan
台湾の島々だけで流通しているわけではありません
Main Island Outer Island
本島 外島
also spread out
も広がりました
like arriving in the philippines
フィリピンに来たような
Arrive in South Vietnam
南ベトナムに到着
Also to the south of Thailand
タイの南にもあります
So the range is very wide
なので範囲がとても広いです
this thing
このこと
can make us go very wow
私たちをとても驚かせることができます
The wisdom and abilities of the ancients
古代人の知恵と能力
this is
これは
did these scientific analyzes
これらの科学的分析を行いました
To show what is expected of Taiwan and surrounding areas
台湾とその周辺地域に期待されるものを示す
Expected Relationships in Other Regions
他地域で期待される関係
This is what the entire expectation finds
これが期待全体の結果です
such a zone
そんなゾーン
Because Taiwan has always been very popular
台湾は昔から人気が高いので
we can forget about it
私たちはそれを忘れることができます
so
それで
Well, my relationship at this time
さて、この時の私の関係
I'm probably past the time
もう時期を過ぎてしまったのかもしれない
So so our archeology
私たちの考古学もそうです
Research on ancient humans in Taiwan
台湾における古代人類の研究
In fact, through archaeological research
実際、考古学的研究を通じて
In fact, it broadens our horizons for Taiwanese
実際、台湾人に対する視野が広がります。
we are not living at home
私たちは家に住んでいません
Our current Taiwanese
現在の台湾人
Taiwanese have tens of thousands of years of history
台湾人には数万年の歴史がある
continue history
歴史を続ける
then this help
それならこのヘルプ
Now we can take people from Taiwan
これで台湾から人を連れて行けるようになりました
It can also be from 30,000 years to 400 years
30,000年から400年にも及ぶ可能性があります
can be divided into many different paragraphs
多くの異なる段落に分割できます
people of different ages
さまざまな年齢の人
then this is a chronology
それからこれは年表です
This is my personal build
これは私の個人的なビルドです
as can be seen
見てわかるように
The earlier the more simple
早ければ早いほどシンプル
it's getting late
遅くなってきたよ
The more culturally differentiated
文化的に差別化が進むほど
in different regions for different cultures
異なる地域の異なる文化
Representing cultural diversity
文化の多様性を表現する
this so from these things
これはこういうことから
We can find a common
共通点を見つけることができます
similarity locus
類似性軌跡
The first one is Takuko outside Atom Island
1人目はアトム島外の拓子
All cultures from ancient times to the present
古代から現代までのあらゆる文化
It has been from outside the island since 30,000 years ago
3万年前から島外から伝わってきた
Came here from Southeast Asia
東南アジアから来ました
The second is the expansion of the interior of the coast
2つ目は海岸内部の拡大です。
are slowly expanding from the coast to the inland
沿岸部から内陸部まで徐々に拡大している
like early prehistoric times
先史時代の初期のように
or Han Chinese
または漢民族
That is, from the coast to the inland slowly
つまり海岸から内陸へゆっくりと
expand slowly
ゆっくりと拡大する
another third
さらに3分の1
Diversification of Taiwan's terrain and environment
台湾の地形環境の多様化
Therefore, a lot of local environment-adapted
したがって、地域の環境に適応した多くの
these cultures
これらの文化
The appearance of different cultures
異文化の登場
So represent a very full kind of
したがって、非常に完全な種類の
Variety of Ecological Adaptations
さまざまな生態学的適応
diversity
多様性
The fourth is the island of Taiwan
4つ目は台湾島です
So since ancient times
だから昔から
Coastal trade is an important
沿岸貿易は重要です
you see from thousands of years ago
何千年も前から見えます
Anticipated Hanwai Interactive Transactions
予想されるハンワイ・インタラクティブ・トランザクション
Until the era of popular sentiment
大衆感情の時代まで
Trade between Taiwan's aborigines and Han Chinese
台湾原住民と漢民族との貿易
It was Penghu and the main island four or five thousand years ago
4、5千年前は澎湖と本島でした
In fact, this maritime transaction has always been a very constant behavior pattern
実際、この海上取引は常に非常に一定の行動パターンでした。
sorry
ごめん
Finally, we give some enlightenment to the Taiwanese
最後に、台湾人への啓発を行います。
What kind of enlightenment do we get from these studies?
これらの研究からどのような啓発が得られるのでしょうか?
The first one is the favorite small island marine military area
1つ目はお気に入りの小さな島の海上軍事エリアです
Taiwan is a small island, but in all directions
台湾は小さな島ですが、四方八方にあります
These people can come to Taiwan from all directions
この人たちはあらゆる方向から台湾に来ることができます
keep coming in waves
波が来続ける
first come first serve
早い者勝ち
The third is the continuous development of the sea railway
第三に、海上鉄道の継続的な発展です。
Taiwan's topography and landforms are constantly changing
台湾の地形と地形は常に変化しています
But human beings have nothing to do with adapting to the environment
しかし、人間は環境に適応することとは何の関係もありません
It can continue to develop from nearly ten thousand years to the present
約1万年から現在まで発展し続けることができます
Then Bilu men and women actually have success
そうすればビルの男性も女性も実際に成功する
It's all worked out
すべてうまくいきました
look at ancient life
古代の生活を見てください
It has to adapt to the environment
環境に適応しなければならない
Utilize the best strategies
最適な戦略を活用する
and get the best life
そして最高の人生を手に入れましょう
and until now
そして今まで
so finally
それでついに
I have some thoughts
いくつか考えがあります
In fact, we feel that what we just saw on the first page
実際、最初のページで見たものが次のように感じられます。
Many people are arguing about who is Taiwanese.
誰が台湾人なのかについて多くの人が議論しています。
Looking at it online, I think some are ridiculous
ネットで見るとおかしなものもあると思います
really ridiculous
本当にばかばかしい
there is bullshit
でたらめがあります
or some are simply stubborn
あるいは単に頑固な人もいる
or how
あるいはどうやって
In fact, I think we don't need to spend time fighting over who is Taiwanese.
実際、誰が台湾人であるかを争うために時間を費やす必要はないと思います。
In fact, from these ancient people
実際、これらの古代の人々から
experienced history looks
経験豊富な歴史の外観
The people who live and work hard on this land are Taiwanese
この地で暮らし、懸命に働く人々は台湾人です
these ancient ancients
これらの古代の古代人
You can see that they slowly reproduce his descendants in this land bit by bit
少しずつゆっくりと彼の子孫をこの地に再現していくのがわかる
then until now
それから今まで
where especially in today's global competition
特に今日の世界的な競争においては
Era of not advancing or retreating
前進も後退もしない時代
Should we Taiwanese not be able to disagree?
私たち台湾人は同意できないのでしょうか？
Our Taiwan now looks more and more regressive
私たちの台湾はますます退行的に見えるようになりました
Well, this is a very boring psychology.
まあ、これは非常に退屈な心理学です。
Recently our Ma Ying-jeou is also bored
最近うちの馬英九も退屈してる
it's definitely boring
それは間違いなく退屈です
Because Taiwan is not progressing
台湾は進歩してないから
Make everyone the most bored
みんなを一番退屈させる
So I hope everyone will come together to disagree
だから、みんなが団結して反対することを願っています
OK
OK
thank you all
皆さん、ありがとうございました
Thanks
ありがとう
There are only five minutes left for Mr. Zhang's wonderful service and protection.
張さんの素晴らしい奉仕と保護に残された時間はわずか 5 分です。
But we allow three problems
しかし、我々は 3 つの問題を許容します
First
初め
there is a third
3番目があります
that's all
それで全部です
Thank you, teacher
ありがとう、先生
Super wonderful speech
超素晴らしいスピーチ
Do not know at all
全く分からない
Archaeological lectures will be so passionate
考古学の講義はとても熱心になります
and so funny
そしてとても面白い
what i want to ask is
私が聞きたいのは
One of the places I'm most interested in is
私が最も興味を持っている場所の一つは、
Questions about the first dog in Taiwan
台湾初の犬についての質問
The teacher just mentioned that
先ほど先生がおっしゃいました
The first dog in Taiwan was buried well
台湾初の犬が無事に埋葬された
say with common imagination
一般的な想像力に
Dogs may die in some villages
村によっては犬が死ぬかもしれない
Just throw it away, it doesn't seem to be the same
捨ててください、同じではないようです
But you just mentioned that
しかし、あなたは今言いました
These people should be from South China
この人たちは中国南部出身のはずだ
They are also used to coming from South China
彼らは中国南部から来ることにも慣れています
Want to keep their original village habits
村本来の習慣を守りたい
Because after all the environment is also similar
やっぱり環境も似てるから
But if they are in their hometown
でももし彼らが故郷にいたら
The general imagination is to throw the dog away
一般的な想像では犬を捨てることです
Then why do you love dogs so much when you come to Taiwan?
では、なぜ台湾に来るとそんなに犬が好きなのでしょうか？
mean the dog they brought
彼らが連れてきた犬のことです
So the feeling is very good
なので感触はとても良いです
or in the hometown
それとも地元で
the dog they brought
彼らが連れてきた犬
So the feeling is very good
なので感触はとても良いです
Or the dog in Taiwan
あるいは台湾の犬
The special reason they feel getting along
彼らが仲良くなっていると感じる特別な理由
Or, does the teacher have some explanations for this place?
それとも、先生からこの場所についての説明はありますか？
That is to say, he seems to be
つまり、彼はそうであるようです
Or the part that seems to be different from the original imagination
あるいは当初の想像と違うと思われる部分
Thanks
ありがとう
Because I don't know how they are in the opposite corner of South China
なぜなら、彼らが中国南部の反対側の隅でどうなっているかわからないからです。
Maybe it's fun too Maybe
それも楽しいかも知れません
do not know
わかりません
Then this is indeed what we can see from our archaeological phenomena
そうすると、まさにこれが考古学的現象から分かることなのです
it is so
それはそうです
This is a dog, look at this, it deliberately buries its smoke
これは犬です、これを見てください、意図的に煙を埋めます
And then let it go to sleep
そしてそのまま寝かせます
It's not good to throw it away
捨てるのは良くないよ
I take good care of the door
玄関を大切にしています
between human and dog
人間と犬の間で
I think the whole society at that time
当時の社会全体が
Dogs are very important to their upbringing
犬はしつけにおいて非常に重要です
He was hunted and mutilated
彼は追われ、切断された
Probably
おそらく
But Nianwei must be the number one dog in Taiwan
でも、ニアンウェイは台湾でナンバーワンの犬に違いない
so far
ここのところ
Doctor Zhang, please
張医師、お願いします。
That year when you mentioned that it was the Changbing culture
長平文化だと君が言ったあの年
It is now found to be almost 30,000 years ago
約3万年前のものであることが現在判明している
After that, there was another fault for a while
その後、一定期間別の障害が発生しました
Then why is there a fault
ではなぜ故障があるのでしょうか
Are the two faults the same?
2つの欠点は同じですか?
democracy
民主
The next time is according to the present time
次回は現在の時刻に準じます
We are now Taiwan's aboriginal Gao Shanzhu
私たちは今、台湾原住民の高善珠です
Or it doesn't seem to have anything to do with those
それともそれらとは何の関係もないようです
why is this
どうしてこれなの
We are still studying this issue
私たちはこの問題をまだ研究中です
I am now a preliminary
私は今予備役です
I had a speech a while ago and I also mentioned
少し前にスピーチをしたときにも言いましたが、
This gap is obvious
このギャップは一目瞭然
From about 15,000 onwards
15,000くらいから
The next session will be about 6000, 5000 years
次のセッションは約6000年か5000年後だろう
There is a GAP in the middle like this
このように真ん中にGAPがあります
Then this GAP
するとこのギャップが
it's on culture
それは文化に関するものです
It has basically not entered the new era
基本的に新しい時代に入っていない
So its period is still typed
したがって、ピリオドはまだ入力されています
hardly naughty
ほとんどいたずらではない
not like this
こんなんじゃない
but it has some differences
しかし、いくつかの違いがあります
it has many tricks
たくさんのトリックがあります
so fake
すごくうそくさい
This real cheat is playing
この本物のチートは遊んでいます
Use real deception instead of verification
検証ではなく本物の欺瞞を使用する
in this way
この上
I'm making a preliminary guess about this
これについて予備的な推測をしています
The same culture is actually more than just long soldiers
同じ文化は実際には長い兵士だけではありません
It was also found once in several places in southern Taiwan
台湾南部の数カ所でも一度発見された
my bold guess
私の大胆な推測
This is similar to that of many tribes in Taiwan in the past
これはかつての台湾の多くの部族と同様です
a legend little black person like relationship
伝説の小さな黒人のような関係
Well, this thing is very similar to the Philippines
まあ、これはフィリピンとよく似ています。
Now five or six thousand years ago there were still little black people
さて、5、6,000年前にはまだ小さな黒人がいました
Taiwan is in many tribes
台湾には多くの部族がいる
There are also legends about little black people in the aboriginal tribes
先住民族には小さな黒人についての伝説もあります
In the end it was obviously Saisiyat
結局は明らかにサイシャットだった
It doesn't matter between these little black men
この小さな黒人男性の間ではそれは問題ではありません
I think it's worth thinking about
考えてみる価値はあると思う
So recently I was also discussing such a question
それで最近、私もそのような質問について議論していました
Because the aborigines in Taiwan are pushing up
台湾の原住民が押し上げているから
Pushing it to 2000 will not make it up
2000まで押し上げても補えない
But in many tribal legends
しかし、多くの部族の伝説では
There are many, many legends with little black people
小さな黒人に関する伝説はたくさんあります
dwarf legend
ドワーフの伝説
The legend but now the dwarves are gone
伝説だが今はドワーフはいなくなった
Is it possible that this thing is such a group of people?
もしかして、これってそういう人の集まりなのでしょうか？
from the Philippines
フィリピンから
This part I'm here for a bold
この部分は大胆に表現するためにここにいます
currently it is a guess
現時点では推測です
Maybe we need to go further and do some discussions
もっと踏み込んで議論する必要があるかもしれない
But between the CAP of the Chinese Academy of Sciences and the longevity culture
しかし、中国科学院のCAPと長寿文化の間には
It should have nothing to do with the ethnic group.
民族かどうかは関係ないはずだ。
in this way
この上
Okay, thank you
大丈夫ありがとう
There is also a problem
問題もあります
consult
相談する
Ask Professor Zhang
張教授に聞く
Just saw that in the picture
写真で見ただけです
That front tooth is missing
その前歯が欠けています
The professor said it was
教授はそうだと言いました
Aboriginal people have this tooth extraction custom
アボリジニにはこの抜歯習慣がある
then ask the professor
それから教授に聞いてください
How can there be such a tooth extraction
どうしたらそんな抜歯ができるんだろう
What does it mean
どういう意味ですか
right this this
そう、これ、これ
like what is a needle
針とは何なのかのように
yes this is actually
はい、これは実際にあります
in time era
時代の中で
this tooth extraction practice
この抜歯の練習
eastward across the continent
大陸を東に越えて
down from Shandong
山東省から下る
This is available in Taiwan
こちらは台湾でも購入可能です
Many can be found with the practice of tooth extraction
多くは抜歯の実践で見つかります
aborigines until now
今までの原住民
like the strugglers
闘争者たちのように
there will be many more
もっとたくさんあるでしょう
until now no more
今まではもうない
at least until the sun rises
少なくとも日が昇るまでは
There is also the custom of tooth extraction
抜歯の習慣もある
Then this is in a biological theory
そうすると、これは生物学的な理論で言えば、
Well like some of you grown up
まあ、あなた方の何人かが大人になったように
He is going to use the adult theory
彼は大人の理論を使うつもりだ
in this way
この上
Some are in a special
一部は特別仕様になっています
under this requirement
この要件の下で
like military exploits
軍事的功績のような
Or the girl is an adult
それとも女の子が大人になったのか
he will also pull teeth
彼も歯を抜くでしょう
Then we are within the will of Taiwan
そうすれば我々は台湾の意志の中に入る
also found
も見つかりました
In some tribes, all boys have their teeth pulled
一部の部族では、男の子は全員歯を抜かれています
But in some tribes, both boys and girls pull their teeth
しかし一部の部族では、男の子も女の子も歯を抜く
So it represents the customs and habits of each tribe
つまり、各部族の習慣や習慣を表しているのです
basically different
基本的に違う
Of course tooth extraction will hurt
もちろん抜歯は痛いです
no pain
痛みはありません
its habit like we used to
私たちが以前のようにその習慣
This woman like the Chinese wants to have small feet
この中国人のような女性は足が小さいことを望んでいます
It hurts to have too small feet
足が小さすぎると痛い
right
右
she never had small feet
彼女は足が小さいことは一度もなかった
she became a custom
彼女は習慣になった
everybody do this
みんなこれをする
You feel a shame if you don't pull your teeth
歯を抜かないと恥ずかしいと思う
don't pull your feet
足を引っ張らないでください
that's a shame
残念です
So this becomes a
したがって、これは次のようになります
a customary habit
習慣的な習慣
a ceremony
儀式
so she has to follow
だから彼女は従わなければならない
a constraint of such a culture
そのような文化の制約
in this way
この上
this is incredible
これが信じられない
Thanks
ありがとう
it's raining today
今日は雨です
Thank you very much for being so active
たくさん活動していただき本当にありがとうございました
Archeology is hard work
考古学は大変な仕事だ
and requires cross-disciplinary knowledge
分野を超えた知識が必要です
In fact, a lot of natural science knowledge is needed
実際には多くの自然科学の知識が必要です
and really hard
そして本当に難しい
It's hard to get a little knowledge
ちょっとした知識を得るのは難しい
I remember that Mr. Zhang wanted to
張さんがこう言いたかったのを覚えています。
Ask me to see the Eight Immortals Cave Ruins
八仙の洞窟跡を見てほしいと頼んでください
I see so high
とても高いところに見えます
I'm going to do it for so long and dare not say
ずっとやるつもりだからあえて言わない
But they are walking on flat ground
でも彼らは平らな地面を歩いている
The quantitative guide that Mr. Chen Zhongyi talked about last time is also
前回陳忠儀氏が話した定量的なガイドも、
The first two graduates who are both very tall
最初の卒業生2名はどちらも背が高いです
so it's really not easy
それは本当に簡単ではありません
organize an archeology
考古学を組織する
The test pile with Master Jing is like Master Jing's army
マスター・ジンとのテストパイルはマスター・ジンの軍隊のようなものです
It's really like Jing Ye's army
まさにジンイェ軍みたいですね
There are many different kinds of people
いろいろな人がいる
Like those post-production studies on the Nanke site
Nanke サイトでのポストプロダクション研究のように
It's all in that railway warehouse.
それはすべてあの鉄道倉庫にあります。
Various charts in the large warehouse
広い倉庫にある各種チャート
just wow like forming an army
軍隊を組織するみたいにすごい
Be prepared to be romantic like a lamp stove
ランプストーブのようにロマンチックになる準備をしてください
So this is very complicated and very hard
これは非常に複雑で非常に困難です
It is not easy to gain some knowledge
ある程度の知識を得るのは簡単ではない
We thank Academician Zhang for his wonderful speech today
本日は張学術院士の素晴らしい講演に感謝します。
Thanks
ありがとう